<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Pawn Diary: SpeakUp</name>
  <author>aimmlegate</author>
  <packageId>aimmlegate.pawndiary.adapter.speakup</packageId>
  <modVersion IgnoreIfNoMatchingField="True">0.1.0</modVersion>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <!-- Pawn Diary owns the Def type and integration API used here. SpeakUp is a hard dependency for
       normal installation because this adapter exists only to classify its interactions and observe
       its transient Talk objects. The code still guards every reflection target and the XML stays
       package-gated, so a force-loaded adapter fails inert instead of crashing when SpeakUp is absent. -->
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>aimmlegate.pawndiary.development</packageId>
      <displayName>Pawn Diary</displayName>
    </li>
    <li>
      <packageId>JPT.speakup</packageId>
      <displayName>SpeakUp</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2502518544</steamWorkshopUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>aimmlegate.pawndiary.development</li>
    <li>JPT.speakup</li>
  </loadAfter>
  <description>Gives SpeakUp's conversations a proper place in Pawn Diary.

- Deep talks, jokes, prisoner conversations, thought reactions and everyday chatter each get their own diary voice — and the diary keeps the lines pawns actually said as raw material.
- A longer exchange (three replies or more, adjustable) can become one shared conversation event for both colonists. On by default; toggle it in this mod's settings.

If a SpeakUp update changes its internals, only the whole-conversation layer switches itself off — everything else keeps working. Requires Pawn Diary and SpeakUp.

———

Даёт разговорам SpeakUp достойное место в Pawn Diary.

- Глубокие разговоры, шутки, беседы с пленниками, реакции на мысли и повседневная болтовня получают в дневнике собственный голос, а реплики поселенцев сохраняются как материал для записи.
- Длинный обмен репликами (от трёх ответов, настраивается) может стать одним общим событием разговора для обоих собеседников. Включено по умолчанию; отключается в настройках мода.

Если обновление SpeakUp поменяет его внутреннее устройство, отключится только слой целых разговоров — остальное продолжит работать. Требуются Pawn Diary и SpeakUp.</description>
</ModMetaData>
