<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Pawn Diary (Beta)</name>
  <author>aimmlegate</author>
  <modIconPath IgnoreIfNoMatchingField="True">UI/PawnDiaryModIcon</modIconPath>
  <packageId>aimmlegate.pawndiary.development</packageId>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <!-- Pawn Diary uses HarmonyLib to patch base-game choke points (see Source/Patches/). RimWorld
       1.6 no longer ships 0Harmony.dll in its Managed folder, so we both bundle a copy in
       1.6/Assemblies/ (keeps the mod runnable from a bare clone) and declare the standalone
       Harmony mod as a dependency here so load-ordering tools place it first. -->
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
      <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
      <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/Harmony/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
  </loadAfter>
  <description>BETA / WORK IN PROGRESS - expect rough edges, changing defaults, and ongoing prompt tuning; output quality depends on your model and settings.

Pawn Diary gives RimWorld colonists a private journal. It watches meaningful colony moments - social interactions, fights, mental breaks, raids, medicine, crafting, work, mood events, thoughts, arrivals, deaths, and end-of-day reflections - then asks a local or OpenAI-compatible language model to rewrite them as short diary pages in each colonist's own voice.

Entries appear in a per-colonist Diary tab. Two-colonist events get paired points of view, so each pawn can remember the same moment differently. Arrivals and deaths bookend a pawn's story with neutral pages, and optional writing styles shape each voice without touching gameplay.

LLM SUPPORT
Works with any OpenAI-compatible /chat/completions endpoint, plus the OpenAI Responses API. Built around compact prompts for small to mid-size local models (roughly 4-32B) through tools such as LM Studio, llama.cpp, and Ollama. Default endpoint: http://localhost:1234. Configure endpoints, models, API keys, concurrency, prompts, writing styles, and event groups in the mod settings.

Storytelling only: it does not change gameplay, add needs/hediffs/jobs, or write external save data beyond diary entries stored in your RimWorld save. Safe to add to an existing save; removing it stops diary capture and hides the Diary UI/history without leaving custom gameplay defs/components behind. Targets base RimWorld 1.6 and keeps paid DLC content optional.</description>
</ModMetaData>
