<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Pawn Diary: Rimpsyche</name>
  <author>aimmlegate</author>
  <packageId>aimmlegate.pawndiary.adapter.rimpsyche</packageId>
  <modVersion IgnoreIfNoMatchingField="True">0.1.0</modVersion>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <!-- Both are true assembly/load-order dependencies:
       - Pawn Diary owns the public integration API and DiaryInteractionGroupDef XML type.
       - Rimpsyche owns RimPsyche.dll, whose documented personality tracker this adapter reads.
       Harmony is supplied transitively by Rimpsyche's own hard dependency and is never bundled. -->
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>aimmlegate.pawndiary.development</packageId>
      <displayName>Pawn Diary</displayName>
    </li>
    <li>
      <packageId>Maux36.Rimpsyche</packageId>
      <displayName>Rimpsyche - Personality Core</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/3535112473</steamWorkshopUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
    <li>aimmlegate.pawndiary.development</li>
    <li>Maux36.Rimpsyche</li>
  </loadAfter>
  <description>Brings Rimpsyche's personality model into Pawn Diary.

- Rimpsyche conversations reach the diary: ordinary talk folds into the day's social notes, while an unusually charged exchange can become an entry of its own.
- Each colonist's psyche colors their writing: the strongest traits and a couple of interests, in plain words — raw personality numbers never enter the prompt.
- On by default, Rimpsyche can also shape a pawn's diary outlook and record how charged conversations ended. Turn the outlook off and the bridge cleanly releases everything it set.

Nothing is ever written back into Rimpsyche. Requires Pawn Diary and Rimpsyche - Personality Core; inert while Rimpsyche is absent.

———

Приводит модель характера Rimpsyche в Pawn Diary.

- Разговоры Rimpsyche попадают в дневник: обычная беседа вплетается в заметки дня, а необычно острый разговор может стать отдельной записью.
- Психика поселенца окрашивает его слог: самые выраженные черты и пара увлечений, простыми словами — «сырые» числа характера в запрос не попадают.
- По умолчанию Rimpsyche также задаёт поселенцу взгляд дневника и записывает исход острых разговоров. Выключите взгляд — и мост аккуратно снимет всё, что успел установить.

Обратно в Rimpsyche ничего не записывается. Требуются Pawn Diary и Rimpsyche - Personality Core; без Rimpsyche мост бездействует.</description>
</ModMetaData>
