<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  <rimtalk_chatter.label>RimTalk conversations</rimtalk_chatter.label>
  <rimtalk_chatter.instruction>ordinary conversation during the day - treat it as passing talk unless mood, need, or the pair&apos;s history makes a line land harder</rimtalk_chatter.instruction>
  <rimtalk_chatter.instructions.0>day-to-day talk - pick the one supplied line or moment that left a trace, and why it did</rimtalk_chatter.instructions.0>
  <rimtalk_chatter.instructions.1>day-to-day talk - write the feeling under the words: ease, friction, or distance</rimtalk_chatter.instructions.1>
  <rimtalk_chatter.instructions.2>day-to-day talk - keep it small and true; no invented quotes beyond the supplied lines</rimtalk_chatter.instructions.2>
  <rimtalk_chatter.tone>with light, everyday social texture</rimtalk_chatter.tone>
  <romance.label>Romance &amp; dating</romance.label>
  <romance.instruction>a spark between two people—an advance, a stolen glance, a whispered promise, or a heart breaking</romance.instruction>
  <romance.instructions.0>romance — use body cues already supplied or clearly implied: distance, breath, hesitation, or touch if stated</romance.instructions.0>
  <romance.instructions.1>romance — use the unsaid pressure: what the POV notices, holds back, or fears; do not add a new confession or private scene</romance.instructions.1>
  <romance.instructions.2>romance — write the moment after: the pause, the read of the other face, and the changed tension, only from supplied consequences</romance.instructions.2>
  <romance.tone>with tender, fluttering warmth</romance.tone>
  <romance_relation.label>Romance milestones</romance_relation.label>
  <romance_relation.instruction>a relationship becoming official, formalized, or broken; center the change between the two people without treating it like a chat log</romance_relation.instruction>
  <romance_relation.tone>with intimate emotional weight</romance_relation.tone>
  <recruit.label>Recruitment &amp; prison</recruit.label>
  <recruit.instruction>the dance of captor and captive—building rapport, breaking will, or planting seeds of rebellion</recruit.instruction>
  <recruit.tone>with measured, calculating tension</recruit.tone>
  <slavery.label>Slavery</slavery.label>
  <slavery.instruction>the weight of chains—suppression by an overseer or the first spark of defiance</slavery.instruction>
  <slavery.tone>with grim, heavy unease</slavery.tone>
  <conversion.label>Ideology &amp; conversion</conversion.label>
  <conversion.instruction>a battle of belief—conversion, counseling, preaching, or the pressure of faith on faith</conversion.instruction>
  <conversion.tone>with fervent, pressing conviction</conversion.tone>
  <trial.label>Trials &amp; accusations</trial.label>
  <trial.instruction>the weight of judgment—an accusation hurled, a defense mounted, before watching eyes</trial.instruction>
  <trial.tone>with tense, formal pressure</trial.tone>
  <strangechat.label>Strange chat</strangechat.label>
  <strangechat.instruction>something wrong in ordinary conversation--a strange chat that leaves unease lingering. Don&apos;t explain it away</strangechat.instruction>
  <strangechat.tone>with creeping dread; never resolve the wrongness</strangechat.tone>
  <anomaly.label>Anomaly &amp; dark</anomaly.label>
  <anomaly.instruction>something wrong in an ordinary exchange: a voice, phrase, look, or silence leaves unease lingering. Keep it close to the pawn&apos;s senses and don&apos;t explain it away</anomaly.instruction>
  <anomaly.tone>with crawling, skin-prickling wrongness; ordinary details feel unsafe</anomaly.tone>
  <insults.label>Insults &amp; fights</insults.label>
  <insults.instruction>the sting of contempt—an insult, a slight, or fists about to fly</insults.instruction>
  <insults.instructions.0>an insult or slight — use the supplied social text as the sting; do not invent exact wording</insults.instructions.0>
  <insults.instructions.1>an insult or slight — write the body&apos;s reaction: heat, jaw, breath, posture</insults.instructions.1>
  <insults.instructions.2>an insult or slight — write the aftermath in the room: supplied silence, tension, or what the POV does next; do not invent exact words</insults.instructions.2>
  <insults.tone>with sharp, stinging heat</insults.tone>
  <ritual.label>Rituals &amp; speeches</ritual.label>
  <ritual.instruction>a solemn public moment—ritual, ceremony, or address. The colony watches</ritual.instruction>
  <ritual.tone>with solemn, ceremonial weight</ritual.tone>
  <animal.label>Animal handling</animal.label>
  <animal.instruction>a quiet bond—chatting with an animal, taming, training, or letting one go</animal.instruction>
  <animal.tone>with quiet, gentle fondness</animal.tone>
  <heartfelt.label>Heartfelt talk</heartfelt.label>
  <heartfelt.instruction>warmth exchanged—a deep talk, kind words, or a gentle hand steadying someone</heartfelt.instruction>
  <heartfelt.tone>with soft, tender warmth</heartfelt.tone>
  <teaching.label>Teaching &amp; lessons</teaching.label>
  <teaching.instruction>a lesson passed down—an adult teaching or playing with a child</teaching.instruction>
  <teaching.tone>with patient, quiet fondness</teaching.tone>
  <smalltalk.label>Small talk</smalltalk.label>
  <smalltalk.instruction>idle chatter—low-stakes small talk that fills the silence</smalltalk.instruction>
  <smalltalk.instructions.0>small talk — use the supplied topic if present; otherwise let the ordinary rhythm carry the entry</smalltalk.instructions.0>
  <smalltalk.instructions.1>small talk — write the feeling under it: ease, awkwardness, duty, or distance</smalltalk.instructions.1>
  <smalltalk.instructions.2>small talk — write the pauses and back-and-forth without inventing a new topic</smalltalk.instructions.2>
  <smalltalk.tone>with light, easy familiarity</smalltalk.tone>
  <dayreflection.label>Day&apos;s reflection</dayreflection.label>
  <dayreflection.instruction>a quiet end-of-day reflection looking back on the whole day</dayreflection.instruction>
  <dayreflection.tone>with a quiet, settling, end-of-day calm</dayreflection.tone>
  <arrival.label>Arrival</arrival.label>
  <other.label>A quiet day</other.label>
  <other.instruction>a social interaction between the pawns</other.instruction>
  <socialfight.label>Social fights</socialfight.label>
  <socialfight.instruction>tempers snapped—two people came to blows. Write it as heat and impact</socialfight.instruction>
  <socialfight.tone>with raw, adrenal fury</socialfight.tone>
  <insultspree.label>Insult sprees</insultspree.label>
  <insultspree.instruction>a pawn breaking into repeated verbal cruelty; prefer the actual insult log entries when they are recorded</insultspree.instruction>
  <insultspree.tone>with sour, needling anger</insultspree.tone>
  <mentalbreak.label>Mental breaks</mentalbreak.label>
  <mentalbreak.instruction>the mind breaking—write the pawn&apos;s inner storm and what they did</mentalbreak.instruction>
  <mentalbreak.instructions.0>a mental break — write the pressure loop: the repeated thought or urge behind the named state</mentalbreak.instructions.0>
  <mentalbreak.instructions.1>a mental break — write it through body and motion: hands, feet, breath, and the supplied action</mentalbreak.instructions.1>
  <mentalbreak.instructions.2>a mental break — write the world narrowing: one simple sensation, then the state taking over</mentalbreak.instructions.2>
  <mentalbreak.tone>with frayed, overwhelmed intensity</mentalbreak.tone>
  <talecombat.label>Combat, injuries &amp; death</talecombat.label>
  <talecombat.instruction>blood and danger—combat, injury, death, or rescue. Write what it felt like to live through it</talecombat.instruction>
  <talecombat.instructions.0>combat, injury, or rescue — open on a supplied sound cue if present; otherwise open on immediate danger without inventing a battle outcome</talecombat.instructions.0>
  <talecombat.instructions.1>combat, injury, or rescue — open on body impact only when supported: pain, heat, breath, or the injury already supplied</talecombat.instructions.1>
  <talecombat.instructions.2>combat, injury, or rescue — use another pawn only if supplied; otherwise stay with the POV surviving the moment</talecombat.instructions.2>
  <talecombat.tone>with fear and visceral danger</talecombat.tone>
  <talehealth.label>Health &amp; medicine</talehealth.label>
  <talehealth.instruction>the body&apos;s fragility—surgery, illness, exposure, or recovery. Write fear, relief, or trust</talehealth.instruction>
  <talehealth.tone>with fragile fear and relief</talehealth.tone>
  <talelife.label>Life milestones</talelife.label>
  <talelife.instruction>a turning point—birth, capture, bonding, or a new beginning. Write it as a life changed</talelife.instruction>
  <talelife.tone>with the quiet weight of a turning point</talelife.tone>
  <talequality.label>Masterworks &amp; legendary crafts</talequality.label>
  <talequality.instruction>hands that made something lasting—pride, exhaustion, and the weight of creation</talequality.instruction>
  <talequality.tone>with proud, bone-tired satisfaction</talequality.tone>
  <talework.label>Work &amp; achievements</talework.label>
  <talework.instruction>the satisfaction of labor—craft, study, mining, or a skill grown. Keep it proud but grounded</talework.instruction>
  <talework.tone>with steady, grounded pride</talework.tone>
  <taleanomaly.label>Anomaly horror</taleanomaly.label>
  <taleanomaly.instruction>anomaly, mutation, void contact, or unnatural aftermath; write dread as something witnessed up close - smell, light, skin, memory - and never explain the source</taleanomaly.instruction>
  <taleanomaly.tone>with dread and the uncanny, close enough to contaminate the page</taleanomaly.tone>
  <taleincident.label>Raids, disasters &amp; colony events</taleincident.label>
  <taleincident.instruction>the colony shaken—raid, disaster, or crisis. Write what it felt like to live through it</taleincident.instruction>
  <taleincident.tone>with reeling, disaster-shocked tension</taleincident.tone>
  <talequiet.label>Quiet personal moments</talequiet.label>
  <talequiet.instruction>a quiet aside—recreation, prayer, or small embarrassment. Brief and personal</talequiet.instruction>
  <talequiet.tone>with small, private quiet</talequiet.tone>
  <taleother.label>A notable day</taleother.label>
  <taleother.instruction>a notable non-social RimWorld tale involving the pawn</taleother.instruction>
  <moodeventPositive.label>Positive mood events</moodeventPositive.label>
  <moodeventPositive.instruction>something lifted—a positive colony-wide event that eases the heart</moodeventPositive.instruction>
  <moodeventPositive.tone>with a lifted, eased spirit</moodeventPositive.tone>
  <moodeventNegative.label>Negative mood events</moodeventNegative.label>
  <moodeventNegative.instruction>something weighing—a negative colony-wide event that strains the spirit</moodeventNegative.instruction>
  <moodeventNegative.tone>with a weighed-down strain</moodeventNegative.tone>
  <moodeventMixed.label>Situationally mixed mood events</moodeventMixed.label>
  <moodeventMixed.instruction>a condition that touches each person differently—write how it feels to this pawn</moodeventMixed.instruction>
  <moodeventMixed.tone>with an uneasy, conditional charge</moodeventMixed.tone>
  <moodeventOther.label>Passing moods</moodeventOther.label>
  <moodeventOther.instruction>a colony-wide event affecting the pawn&apos;s mood</moodeventOther.instruction>
  <thoughtPregnancyFamily.label>Pregnancy memories</thoughtPregnancyFamily.label>
  <thoughtPregnancyFamily.instruction>pregnancy, birth loss, or the end of a pregnancy as intimate family news; write with restraint and do not assume the pawn feels only one simple emotion</thoughtPregnancyFamily.instruction>
  <thoughtPregnancyFamily.tone>with intimate, restrained weight</thoughtPregnancyFamily.tone>
  <thoughtPositive.label>Positive thoughts</thoughtPositive.label>
  <thoughtPositive.instruction>a fleeting lift in spirits—a positive thought that brightened the day. Match the intensity to the mood effect: minor joys get a quiet note, strong ones get warmth and detail</thoughtPositive.instruction>
  <thoughtPositive.instructions.0>a positive thought — use the supplied trigger if present; otherwise write the mood lift itself. Scale it to the effect</thoughtPositive.instructions.0>
  <thoughtPositive.instructions.1>a positive thought — write the body easing: shoulders, breath, a small private smile. Scale it to the mood lift</thoughtPositive.instructions.1>
  <thoughtPositive.instructions.2>a positive thought — write the pull it creates: wanting the feeling to last or the day to turn. Scale it to the mood lift</thoughtPositive.instructions.2>
  <thoughtPositive.tone>with a small, brightening lift</thoughtPositive.tone>
  <thoughtNegative.label>Negative thoughts</thoughtNegative.label>
  <thoughtNegative.instruction>a weight on the mind—a negative thought that lingered. Match the intensity to the mood effect: minor irritations get a passing mention, severe ones get raw emotion and weight</thoughtNegative.instruction>
  <thoughtNegative.instructions.0>a negative thought — use the supplied trigger if present; otherwise write the sting repeating. Scale it to the mood hit</thoughtNegative.instructions.0>
  <thoughtNegative.instructions.1>a negative thought — write the body tightening: jaw, gut, restless hands. Scale it to the mood hit</thoughtNegative.instructions.1>
  <thoughtNegative.instructions.2>a negative thought — write the loop it makes: returning, growing, hard to drop. Scale it to the mood hit</thoughtNegative.instructions.2>
  <thoughtNegative.tone>with a low, nagging weight</thoughtNegative.tone>
  <thoughtOther.label>Passing thoughts</thoughtOther.label>
  <thoughtOther.instruction>a temporary thought that crossed the pawn&apos;s mind. Match the intensity to the mood effect</thoughtOther.instruction>
  <thoughtOther.tone>with a passing, half-felt shift</thoughtOther.tone>
  <inspiration.label>Inspirations</inspiration.label>
  <inspiration.instruction>a sudden useful clarity—write the pawn&apos;s mind catching fire with purpose, grounded in the specific kind of inspiration and any reason the game gives</inspiration.instruction>
  <inspiration.tone>with bright, focused momentum</inspiration.tone>
  <workDarkStudy.label>Dark study work</workDarkStudy.label>
  <workDarkStudy.instruction>dark research that should feel unsettling every time—write the work as intimate contact with something wrong; keep it spooky, sensory, and unresolved</workDarkStudy.instruction>
  <workDarkStudy.tone>with creeping, unresolved dread</workDarkStudy.tone>
  <workPassion.label>Passionate work</workPassion.label>
  <workPassion.instruction>work that touches one of the pawn&apos;s passions—positive, focused, quietly satisfying, without pretending the colony is easy</workPassion.instruction>
  <workPassion.tone>with grounded satisfaction</workPassion.tone>
  <workStrain.label>Straining work</workStrain.label>
  <workStrain.instruction>work that feels dull, grimy, clumsy, or frustrating—negative when it is cleaning/dumb labor or when the pawn lacks skill</workStrain.instruction>
  <workStrain.tone>with weary irritation</workStrain.tone>
  <workRoutine.label>Routine work</workRoutine.label>
  <workRoutine.instruction>ordinary colony work with no strong passion or failure signal—neutral, practical, brief, and grounded in the texture of the task</workRoutine.instruction>
  <workRoutine.tone>with steady, matter-of-fact routine</workRoutine.tone>
  <hediffPartGainedAnomalous.label>Anomalous body changes</hediffPartGainedAnomalous.label>
  <hediffPartGainedAnomalous.instruction>the pawn&apos;s body has grown or received living anomalous flesh; make it intimate and unsettling - warmth under skin, movement where there should be stillness, a pulse or texture that feels borrowed - filtered through the attitude cue, and never explain its biology</hediffPartGainedAnomalous.instruction>
  <hediffPartGainedArtificial.label>Artificial body parts</hediffPartGainedArtificial.label>
  <hediffPartGainedArtificial.instruction>a made thing has joined the pawn&apos;s body; write the weight, fit, useful precision, foreign rhythm, shame, or relief of the new part through the attitude and tier cues</hediffPartGainedArtificial.instruction>
  <hediffPartLostNatural.label>Lost body parts</hediffPartLostNatural.label>
  <hediffPartLostNatural.instruction>the pawn has lost a natural part of themself; write the first strange gap - shock, absence, pain, phantom feeling, bandage weight, or cold practical calculation - through the attitude and cause cues</hediffPartLostNatural.instruction>
  <hediffPregnancy.label>Pregnancy</hediffPregnancy.label>
  <hediffPregnancy.instruction>pregnancy as a life-changing beginning; write the pawn noticing the body, future, fear, hope, or uncertainty without assuming joy</hediffPregnancy.instruction>
  <hediffPregnancy.tone>with intimate uncertainty and quiet weight</hediffPregnancy.tone>
  <hediffLabor.label>Labor</hediffLabor.label>
  <hediffLabor.instruction>labor and birth approaching; write urgency, pain, fear, care, and the threshold before birth without skipping ahead to the baby unless supplied</hediffLabor.instruction>
  <hediffLabor.tone>with urgent bodily strain</hediffLabor.tone>
  <hediffAnomalyCompulsion.label>Anomaly compulsions</hediffAnomalyCompulsion.label>
  <hediffAnomalyCompulsion.instruction>an Anomaly-driven affliction pressing into the pawn&apos;s thoughts or body; write obsession, trance, withdrawal, rage, corpse torment, or inhuman detachment as the named condition supports, without explaining the entity or inventing treatment</hediffAnomalyCompulsion.instruction>
  <hediffAnomalyCompulsion.tone>with intrusive, unnatural pressure on thought and flesh</hediffAnomalyCompulsion.tone>
  <hediffMajorHealth.label>Major health changes</hediffMajorHealth.label>
  <hediffMajorHealth.instruction>a new or worsening health condition that stayed with the pawn through the day</hediffMajorHealth.instruction>
  <hediffMajorHealth.tone>with bodily unease and vulnerability</hediffMajorHealth.tone>
  <raid.label>Raids</raid.label>
  <raid.instruction>the colony facing a raid that has spawned but may still be approaching—warning, weapons grabbed, positions taken, and the held breath before contact. Write anticipation of the fight unless supplied facts show combat already hit</raid.instruction>
  <raid.instructions.0>a raid approaching the colony — open on warning, distance, cover, weather, or the pawn checking a weapon; keep it before or at first contact</raid.instructions.0>
  <raid.instructions.1>the colony bracing for attackers — write the waiting, orders, doors, sandbags, breath, and fear before the fight fully starts</raid.instructions.1>
  <raid.instructions.2>a raid that may not have reached the defenders yet — use smoke, blood, injuries, or aftermath only if supplied; otherwise keep it to preparation, dread, and first sight of danger</raid.instructions.2>
  <raid.tone>with tense, fight-anticipated urgency</raid.tone>
  <ritualRoyal.label>Royal rituals</ritualRoyal.label>
  <ritualRoyal.instruction>a Royalty ritual completed—make the ceremony courtly, title-conscious, psychic, or anima-rooted as the ritual title suggests</ritualRoyal.instruction>
  <ritualRoyal.tone>with formal rank and ritual authority</ritualRoyal.tone>
  <ritualRoyal.tones.0>courtly and charged with rank, title, witnesses, and public authority</ritualRoyal.tones.0>
  <ritualRoyal.tones.1>psyfocus-hushed and tradition-bound, the ceremony larger than one pawn&apos;s body</ritualRoyal.tones.1>
  <ritualChildbirth.label>Childbirth ritual</ritualChildbirth.label>
  <ritualChildbirth.instruction>a childbirth ritual completed—keep the entry medically and emotionally appropriate: pain, care, risk, exhaustion, relief, or fear before mysticism</ritualChildbirth.instruction>
  <ritualChildbirth.tone>with clinical tenderness and bodily urgency</ritualChildbirth.tone>
  <ritualChildbirth.tones.0>medical, intimate, and careful around pain, care, danger, and relief</ritualChildbirth.tones.0>
  <ritualChildbirth.tones.1>tender but unsentimental, focused on the body, helpers, and immediate outcome</ritualChildbirth.tones.1>
  <ritualGravship.label>Gravship launch</ritualGravship.label>
  <ritualGravship.instruction>a gravship departure ceremony completed before destination selection—center preflight checks, countdown, ignition, liftoff anticipation, and crew discipline; do not claim a destination was chosen, travel began, or a landing occurred</ritualGravship.instruction>
  <ritualGravship.tone>with technical pressure and launch-day focus</ritualGravship.tone>
  <ritualGravship.tones.0>technical and procedural, centered on checks, systems, countdown, and readiness</ritualGravship.tones.0>
  <ritualGravship.tones.1>tense and crew-minded, with launch discipline and restrained anticipation</ritualGravship.tones.1>
  <odysseyGravshipLanding.label>Gravship landing</odysseyGravshipLanding.label>
  <odysseyGravshipLanding.instruction>a gravship has successfully arrived—write the supplied journey reason, duration, POV role, ship, origin, and destination as first-person experience; when an exact landing outcome is supplied, weave only that visible consequence into the same landing; treat a quest site only as an arrival, never as quest completion, and invent no hazards or outcomes beyond the supplied facts</odysseyGravshipLanding.instruction>
  <odysseyGravshipLanding.tone>with arrival relief, crew focus, and the weight of a mobile home coming down</odysseyGravshipLanding.tone>
  <odysseyGravshipLanding.tones.0>grounded and sensory, centered on descent, touchdown, and what this destination means</odysseyGravshipLanding.tones.0>
  <odysseyGravshipLanding.tones.1>crew-minded and reflective, weighing the completed passage without inventing what follows</odysseyGravshipLanding.tones.1>
  <ritualAnomalyInvitation.label>Anomaly invitations</ritualAnomalyInvitation.label>
  <ritualAnomalyInvitation.instruction>a psychic ritual meant to call something toward the colony completed—center the pawn&apos;s captured perspective, deliberate invitation, and uncertainty; do not claim what arrived or what happened afterward</ritualAnomalyInvitation.instruction>
  <ritualAnomalyInvitation.tone>with deliberate invitation and uncertain dread</ritualAnomalyInvitation.tone>
  <ritualAnomalyInvitation.tones.0>expectant and uneasy, listening for an answer without deciding what answered</ritualAnomalyInvitation.tones.0>
  <ritualAnomalyInvitation.tones.1>ritual-focused and watchful, dwelling on the choice to call rather than an unverified result</ritualAnomalyInvitation.tones.1>
  <ritualAnomalyFleshAndWeather.label>Flesh and hostile weather rituals</ritualAnomalyFleshAndWeather.label>
  <ritualAnomalyFleshAndWeather.instruction>a psychic ritual meant to make the environment bodily or hostile completed—write the pawn&apos;s supplied role and the deliberate escalation, but do not claim that a threat arrived, harmed anyone, or persisted</ritualAnomalyFleshAndWeather.instruction>
  <ritualAnomalyFleshAndWeather.tone>with deliberate escalation and bodily environmental dread</ritualAnomalyFleshAndWeather.tone>
  <ritualAnomalyFleshAndWeather.tones.0>visceral and apprehensive, focused on choosing to make the world less safe</ritualAnomalyFleshAndWeather.tones.0>
  <ritualAnomalyFleshAndWeather.tones.1>heavy with hostile weather or fleshly expectation, without inventing the aftermath</ritualAnomalyFleshAndWeather.tones.1>
  <ritualAnomalyPredation.label>Predatory psychic rituals</ritualAnomalyPredation.label>
  <ritualAnomalyPredation.instruction>a psychic ritual meant to take skill, years, or psychic capacity from a target completed—attribute agency, victimhood, and sensation only through the supplied perspective and other-pawn facts; do not invent the exact loss or later condition</ritualAnomalyPredation.instruction>
  <ritualAnomalyPredation.tone>with intimate predation and controlled psychic harm</ritualAnomalyPredation.tone>
  <ritualAnomalyPredation.tones.0>close and predatory, attentive to who acted and who endured without swapping their experiences</ritualAnomalyPredation.tones.0>
  <ritualAnomalyPredation.tones.1>morally tense and bodily strange, stopping at the facts the captured perspective can know</ritualAnomalyPredation.tones.1>
  <ritualAnomalyMind.label>Mind-altering psychic rituals</ritualAnomalyMind.label>
  <ritualAnomalyMind.instruction>a psychic ritual meant to alter memory, feeling, or behavior completed—keep each pawn inside the supplied invoker, target, participant, or spectator perspective; do not give one role another pawn&apos;s inner effects</ritualAnomalyMind.instruction>
  <ritualAnomalyMind.tone>with invasive mental pressure and uncertain interior consequence</ritualAnomalyMind.tone>
  <ritualAnomalyMind.tones.0>invasive and disorienting, careful about whose mind the supplied facts describe</ritualAnomalyMind.tones.0>
  <ritualAnomalyMind.tones.1>psychically close but epistemically restrained, never inventing inaccessible memories or feelings</ritualAnomalyMind.tones.1>
  <ritualAnomalyAbduction.label>Skip abduction rituals</ritualAnomalyAbduction.label>
  <ritualAnomalyAbduction.instruction>a psychic ritual meant to pull a person through distance completed—focus on the pawn&apos;s supplied role, reach, and danger; name an abductee or outcome only when the captured target facts explicitly supply it</ritualAnomalyAbduction.instruction>
  <ritualAnomalyAbduction.tone>with distant reach, sudden danger, and incomplete knowledge</ritualAnomalyAbduction.tone>
  <ritualAnomalyAbduction.tones.0>tense across impossible distance, with identity and outcome left uncertain unless supplied</ritualAnomalyAbduction.tones.0>
  <ritualAnomalyAbduction.tones.1>focused on the act of reaching and pulling, not an invented arrival or aftermath</ritualAnomalyAbduction.tones.1>
  <ritualAnomalyDeathRefusal.label>Death-refusal ritual</ritualAnomalyDeathRefusal.label>
  <ritualAnomalyDeathRefusal.instruction>a psychic ritual imbued a target with death refusal—write the choice to establish an unnatural relationship with death from the supplied perspective; do not claim that the target has died or returned</ritualAnomalyDeathRefusal.instruction>
  <ritualAnomalyDeathRefusal.tone>with grave intent and an unfinished bargain with death</ritualAnomalyDeathRefusal.tone>
  <ritualAnomalyDeathRefusal.tones.0>solemn and unnatural, treating the ritual as preparation rather than resurrection</ritualAnomalyDeathRefusal.tones.0>
  <ritualAnomalyDeathRefusal.tones.1>quietly defiant toward death, while leaving any future death or return unclaimed</ritualAnomalyDeathRefusal.tones.1>
  <ritualAnomalyPsychic.label>Psychic rituals</ritualAnomalyPsychic.label>
  <ritualAnomalyPsychic.instruction>an unknown or modded Anomaly psychic ritual completed—use the supplied perspective and visible facts, keep any downstream effect uncertain, and do not invent mechanics or consequences</ritualAnomalyPsychic.instruction>
  <ritualAnomalyPsychic.tone>with occult uncertainty and restrained psychic dread</ritualAnomalyPsychic.tone>
  <ritualAnomalyPsychic.tones.0>unsettling and watchful, grounded in the role and facts that were actually supplied</ritualAnomalyPsychic.tones.0>
  <ritualAnomalyPsychic.tones.1>fragmentary and uncertain, refusing to explain or predict an unknown ritual&apos;s consequence</ritualAnomalyPsychic.tones.1>
  <ritualFinished.label>Rituals</ritualFinished.label>
  <ritualFinished.instruction>a ritual completed—write the ceremony as a social, spiritual, or political moment from the pawn&apos;s assigned place in it</ritualFinished.instruction>
  <ritualFinished.tone>with ceremonial weight and personal consequence</ritualFinished.tone>
  <ritualFinished.tones.0>ceremonial and embodied, attention fixed on role, title, and consequence</ritualFinished.tones.0>
  <ritualFinished.tones.1>formal but personal, the ritual&apos;s public meaning pressing into private thought</ritualFinished.tones.1>
  <abilityPsycast.label>Psycasts</abilityPsycast.label>
  <abilityPsycast.instruction>a psychic ability used—write the moment as focus, willpower, psychic pressure, and visible consequence without inventing extra effects</abilityPsycast.instruction>
  <abilityPsycast.tone>with psychic focus and charged restraint</abilityPsycast.tone>
  <abilityPsycast.tones.0>controlled and psychic, focused on effort, pressure, and the ability&apos;s visible result</abilityPsycast.tones.0>
  <abilityPsycast.tones.1>hushed and forceful, with the mind doing work the body can barely explain</abilityPsycast.tones.1>
  <abilityHostile.label>Combat abilities</abilityHostile.label>
  <abilityHostile.instruction>a hostile ability used in danger—write the activation as a tactical action under pressure, grounded in the supplied ability and target</abilityHostile.instruction>
  <abilityHostile.tone>with tactical pressure and sudden force</abilityHostile.tone>
  <abilityHostile.tones.0>urgent and tactical, centered on the decision to use the power now</abilityHostile.tones.0>
  <abilityHostile.tones.1>sharp and violent, but only as far as the supplied ability facts support</abilityHostile.tones.1>
  <abilityUsed.label>Abilities</abilityUsed.label>
  <abilityUsed.instruction>a pawn used an ability—write the decision, effort, target if supplied, and immediate consequence without adding mechanics or outcomes that were not given</abilityUsed.instruction>
  <abilityUsed.tone>with focused exertion and practical consequence</abilityUsed.tone>
  <abilityUsed.tones.0>focused and concrete, about the moment of use rather than a broad summary</abilityUsed.tones.0>
  <abilityUsed.tones.1>practical and sensory, grounded in the named ability, target, and cooldown rarity</abilityUsed.tones.1>
  <animal.tones.0>soft and patient, focused on trust through action</animal.tones.0>
  <animal.tones.1>practical and warm, fondness shown without sentimentality</animal.tones.1>
  <anomaly.tones.0>skin-prickling and sensory, one ordinary detail made wrong</anomaly.tones.0>
  <anomaly.tones.1>cold and alien, focused on what the pawn cannot make fit</anomaly.tones.1>
  <conversion.tones.0>fervent and declarative, like belief under pressure</conversion.tones.0>
  <conversion.tones.1>inward and doubtful, focused on conviction cracking</conversion.tones.1>
  <dayreflection.tones.0>tired and reflective, weighing what still matters</dayreflection.tones.0>
  <dayreflection.tones.1>softly closing, like the day finally going quiet</dayreflection.tones.1>
  <heartfelt.tones.0>gentle and open, letting warmth show plainly</heartfelt.tones.0>
  <heartfelt.tones.1>quietly held, warmth shown through small restraint</heartfelt.tones.1>
  <hediffAnomalyCompulsion.tones.0>intrusive and wrong, thought or nerve snagging on something outside itself</hediffAnomalyCompulsion.tones.0>
  <hediffAnomalyCompulsion.tones.1>unsettling and compulsive, the mind and body pulled where they should not go</hediffAnomalyCompulsion.tones.1>
  <hediffLabor.tones.0>urgent and bodily, breath and pain setting the pace</hediffLabor.tones.0>
  <hediffLabor.tones.1>threshold-tense, focused on fear, care, and waiting</hediffLabor.tones.1>
  <hediffMajorHealth.tones.0>vulnerable and bodily, symptoms shaping every thought</hediffMajorHealth.tones.0>
  <hediffMajorHealth.tones.1>quietly frightened, weakness changing the day&apos;s scale</hediffMajorHealth.tones.1>
  <hediffPartGainedAnomalous.tones.0>visceral and intimate, flesh answering before the pawn does</hediffPartGainedAnomalous.tones.0>
  <hediffPartGainedAnomalous.tones.1>quiet dread anchored in warmth, pulse, and bodily wrongness</hediffPartGainedAnomalous.tones.1>
  <hediffPartGainedArtificial.tones.0>intimate and practical, the body learning the timing of a new tool</hediffPartGainedArtificial.tones.0>
  <hediffPartGainedArtificial.tones.1>quietly body-aware, machinery and flesh sharing one routine</hediffPartGainedArtificial.tones.1>
  <hediffPartLostNatural.tones.0>bodily and stunned, absence louder than pain</hediffPartLostNatural.tones.0>
  <hediffPartLostNatural.tones.1>raw and practical, loss becoming the body&apos;s new map</hediffPartLostNatural.tones.1>
  <hediffPregnancy.tones.0>body-aware and intimate, uncertainty held close</hediffPregnancy.tones.0>
  <hediffPregnancy.tones.1>future-facing and quiet, hope and fear in balance</hediffPregnancy.tones.1>
  <inspiration.tones.0>bright and decisive, thought turning into a plan</inspiration.tones.0>
  <inspiration.tones.1>electric and restless, purpose pushing the body forward</inspiration.tones.1>
  <insults.tones.0>hot and clipped, like anger held in the teeth</insults.tones.0>
  <insults.tones.1>cold and cutting, focused on the sting afterward</insults.tones.1>
  <insultspree.tones.0>needling and repetitive, like anger looking for targets</insultspree.tones.0>
  <insultspree.tones.1>sour and exhausted, cruelty sounding almost automatic</insultspree.tones.1>
  <mentalbreak.tones.0>fragmented and breathless, thought under too much pressure</mentalbreak.tones.0>
  <mentalbreak.tones.1>numb and sideways, reality narrowed to one impulse</mentalbreak.tones.1>
  <moodeventMixed.tones.0>uneasy and conditional, the pawn unsure how to feel</moodeventMixed.tones.0>
  <moodeventMixed.tones.1>alert and bodily, tracking how the condition lands</moodeventMixed.tones.1>
  <moodeventNegative.tones.0>heavy and low, every detail pressing downward</moodeventNegative.tones.0>
  <moodeventNegative.tones.1>irritated and weathered, strain showing in patience</moodeventNegative.tones.1>
  <moodeventPositive.tones.0>open and eased, letting relief into the sentence</moodeventPositive.tones.0>
  <moodeventPositive.tones.1>quietly grateful, focused on tension leaving the body</moodeventPositive.tones.1>
  <questAccepted.label>Quest accepted</questAccepted.label>
  <questAccepted.instruction>a new quest the colony has taken on—anticipation, curiosity, and the weight of a promise made together. Write the hope or doubt it stirs in this pawn without claiming they alone accepted it</questAccepted.instruction>
  <questAccepted.tone>with anticipation and wary curiosity</questAccepted.tone>
  <questAccepted.tones.0>wary and forward-looking, promise weighed against risk</questAccepted.tones.0>
  <questAccepted.tones.1>curious but guarded, hope kept under practical doubt</questAccepted.tones.1>
  <questCompleted.label>Quest completed</questCompleted.label>
  <questCompleted.instruction>a quest fulfilled through the colony&apos;s common effort—relief, satisfaction, and the cost paid along the way. Write the earned resolution without claiming this pawn alone completed it</questCompleted.instruction>
  <questCompleted.tone>with hard-won relief and quiet satisfaction</questCompleted.tone>
  <questCompleted.tones.0>relieved and settled, like a shared debt finally paid</questCompleted.tones.0>
  <questCompleted.tones.1>tired but proud, satisfaction measured against the colony&apos;s cost</questCompleted.tones.1>
  <questFailed.label>Quest failed</questFailed.label>
  <questFailed.instruction>a quest lost by the colony—regret, grief, and the consequences of the failure. Write the weight of what slipped away without assigning blame to this pawn alone</questFailed.instruction>
  <questFailed.tone>with regret and heavy loss</questFailed.tone>
  <questFailed.tones.0>heavy and regretful, focused on what slipped away from everyone</questFailed.tones.0>
  <questFailed.tones.1>quietly grieving, shared consequence felt more than explained</questFailed.tones.1>
  <raid.tones.0>tense and tactical, waiting for the fight to break open</raid.tones.0>
  <raid.tones.1>urgent but anticipatory, fear gathering before contact</raid.tones.1>
  <raidDropPod.label>Drop-pod raids</raidDropPod.label>
  <raidDropPod.instruction>raiders punching straight into the colony by drop pod—sudden impact, no long warning, danger already inside the perimeter. Write the shock of instant contact</raidDropPod.instruction>
  <raidDropPod.instructions.0>a drop-pod raid landing inside or near the colony — open on impact, alarms, and the scramble before anyone has time to prepare</raidDropPod.instructions.0>
  <raidDropPod.instructions.1>a drop-pod raid with no slow approach — write the first stunned seconds, then the pawn&apos;s immediate choice of cover, weapon, or flight</raidDropPod.instructions.1>
  <raidDropPod.instructions.2>raiders dropping from above — keep it sudden and close; do not write as if there was a long siege or approach unless supplied facts say so</raidDropPod.instructions.2>
  <raidDropPod.tone>with shocked, impact-fast danger</raidDropPod.tone>
  <raidDropPod.tones.0>impact-fast and disoriented, danger already inside the walls</raidDropPod.tones.0>
  <raidDropPod.tones.1>shocked and close-quarters, every sentence reacting to sudden contact</raidDropPod.tones.1>
  <raidFriendly.label>Friendly arrivals &amp; raids</raidFriendly.label>
  <raidFriendly.instruction>a friendly force arriving at the colony—reinforcements, allies, or a peaceful drop. Write the relief or unease they bring</raidFriendly.instruction>
  <raidFriendly.tone>with cautious relief or uneasy gratitude</raidFriendly.tone>
  <raidFriendly.tones.0>cautiously relieved, trust arriving slowly</raidFriendly.tones.0>
  <raidFriendly.tones.1>uneasy and grateful, help still feeling like risk</raidFriendly.tones.1>
  <raidInfestation.label>Infestations</raidInfestation.label>
  <raidInfestation.instruction>an infestation erupting from the colony&apos;s own ground—chitin, tunnels, enclosed panic, and danger already among the rooms. Write it as sudden internal horror, not a normal raid</raidInfestation.instruction>
  <raidInfestation.instructions.0>an infestation breaking open inside the colony — open on sound, dust, claws, darkness, or the room changing from safe to hostile</raidInfestation.instructions.0>
  <raidInfestation.instructions.1>insects bursting from within the base — write cramped fear and immediate survival, not a distant enemy approach</raidInfestation.instructions.1>
  <raidInfestation.instructions.2>an underground threat erupting into lived-in space — keep it close, sensory, and practical; do not invent a resolved fight</raidInfestation.instructions.2>
  <raidInfestation.tone>with claustrophobic, chitin-close panic</raidInfestation.tone>
  <raidInfestation.tones.0>claustrophobic and horrified, safety turning into a breach</raidInfestation.tones.0>
  <raidInfestation.tones.1>close, filthy, and panicked, the threat already underfoot</raidInfestation.tones.1>
  <recruit.tones.0>controlled and strategic, every sentence weighing leverage</recruit.tones.0>
  <recruit.tones.1>tight and wary, focused on power in the room</recruit.tones.1>
  <ritual.tones.0>ceremonial and still, aware of watching eyes</ritual.tones.0>
  <ritual.tones.1>reverent but uneasy, focused on duty and consequence</ritual.tones.1>
  <romance.tones.0>close and physical, with restrained vulnerability</romance.tones.0>
  <romance.tones.1>quietly reflective, focused on what changed</romance.tones.1>
  <romance_relation.tones.0>formal and life-changing, with quiet restraint</romance_relation.tones.0>
  <romance_relation.tones.1>private and raw, focused on the bond shifting</romance_relation.tones.1>
  <rimtalk_chatter.tones.0>loose and conversational, like talk drifting through the room</rimtalk_chatter.tones.0>
  <rimtalk_chatter.tones.1>plain and observant, small words carrying small weights</rimtalk_chatter.tones.1>
  <slavery.tones.0>oppressive and heavy, focused on control</slavery.tones.0>
  <slavery.tones.1>quietly defiant, with anger kept under pressure</slavery.tones.1>
  <smalltalk.tones.0>loose and conversational, carried by small pauses</smalltalk.tones.0>
  <smalltalk.tones.1>plain and companionable, ordinary detail doing the work</smalltalk.tones.1>
  <socialfight.tones.0>fast and physical, driven by impact and breath</socialfight.tones.0>
  <socialfight.tones.1>shocked and aftermath-heavy, anger cooling into consequence</socialfight.tones.1>
  <strangechat.tones.0>ordinary on the surface, wrong underneath</strangechat.tones.0>
  <strangechat.tones.1>quietly uncanny, ending before the wrongness resolves</strangechat.tones.1>
  <taleanomaly.tones.0>uncanny and watchful, every ordinary detail suspect</taleanomaly.tones.0>
  <taleanomaly.tones.1>intimate and contaminated, as if the wrongness followed the pawn home</taleanomaly.tones.1>
  <talecombat.tones.0>visceral and immediate, body first and thought second</talecombat.tones.0>
  <talecombat.tones.1>stunned and aftershock-heavy, danger echoing afterward</talecombat.tones.1>
  <talehealth.tones.0>fragile and clinical, focused on body and risk</talehealth.tones.0>
  <talehealth.tones.1>relieved but shaken, trust or fear still present</talehealth.tones.1>
  <taleincident.tones.0>reeling and urgent, focused on the scramble</taleincident.tones.0>
  <taleincident.tones.1>hollow and stunned, focused on the damage after</taleincident.tones.1>
  <talelife.tones.0>hushed and consequential, aware life has turned</talelife.tones.0>
  <talelife.tones.1>immediate and personal, focused on the first changed breath</talelife.tones.1>
  <talequality.tones.0>proud and tactile, focused on hands and material</talequality.tones.0>
  <talequality.tones.1>bone-tired and satisfied, accomplishment after strain</talequality.tones.1>
  <talequiet.tones.0>private and spare, one small feeling held close</talequiet.tones.0>
  <talequiet.tones.1>light and brief, a passing note rather than a confession</talequiet.tones.1>
  <talework.tones.0>steady and practical, pride kept close to the work</talework.tones.0>
  <talework.tones.1>quietly pleased, focused on skill settling into the body</talework.tones.1>
  <teaching.tones.0>patient and instructive, focused on small progress</teaching.tones.0>
  <teaching.tones.1>playful but grounded, affection shown through attention</teaching.tones.1>
  <thoughtNegative.tones.0>low and nagging, the thought returning in loops</thoughtNegative.tones.0>
  <thoughtNegative.tones.1>tight and bodily, irritation or hurt sitting in the gut</thoughtNegative.tones.1>
  <thoughtOther.tones.0>brief and half-felt, gone almost as it arrives</thoughtOther.tones.0>
  <thoughtOther.tones.1>plain and observational, naming the mood without drama</thoughtOther.tones.1>
  <thoughtPositive.tones.0>small and bright, like tension briefly loosening</thoughtPositive.tones.0>
  <thoughtPositive.tones.1>quietly buoyant, focused on a thought worth keeping</thoughtPositive.tones.1>
  <thoughtPregnancyFamily.tones.0>restrained and intimate, emotion held carefully</thoughtPregnancyFamily.tones.0>
  <thoughtPregnancyFamily.tones.1>body-aware and uncertain, hope and fear both possible</thoughtPregnancyFamily.tones.1>
  <trial.tones.0>formal and brittle, each sentence like testimony</trial.tones.0>
  <trial.tones.1>watched and exposed, focused on shame or defense</trial.tones.1>
  <workDarkStudy.tones.0>close and sensory, dread coming through the work itself</workDarkStudy.tones.0>
  <workDarkStudy.tones.1>quietly contaminated, curiosity feeling like a mistake</workDarkStudy.tones.1>
  <workPassion.tones.0>focused and satisfied, pleasure kept practical</workPassion.tones.0>
  <workPassion.tones.1>absorbed and tactile, passion showing through the task</workPassion.tones.1>
  <workRoutine.tones.0>matter-of-fact and rhythmic, ordinary work continuing</workRoutine.tones.0>
  <workRoutine.tones.1>quietly practical, attention on tools and sequence</workRoutine.tones.1>
  <workStrain.tones.0>weary and blunt, frustration in the hands</workStrain.tones.0>
  <workStrain.tones.1>grimy and resigned, irritation kept under duty</workStrain.tones.1>
  <progressionSkillPassion.label>Passion skill milestone</progressionSkillPassion.label>
  <progressionSkillPassion.instruction>a passion skill milestone; write pride, effort, frustration, or identity through the named skill and level only</progressionSkillPassion.instruction>
  <progressionSkillPassion.tone>with earned self-awareness</progressionSkillPassion.tone>
  <progressionSkillPassion.tones.0>proud but grounded, aware of the labor behind the milestone</progressionSkillPassion.tones.0>
  <progressionSkillPassion.tones.1>quietly intense, treating skill as part of who the pawn is becoming</progressionSkillPassion.tones.1>
  <progressionPsylink.label>Psylink gained</progressionPsylink.label>
  <progressionPsylink.instruction>a psylink level gain; write the psychic change as lived sensation, responsibility, or unease, without inventing new powers</progressionPsylink.instruction>
  <progressionPsylink.tone>with strange inner pressure</progressionPsylink.tone>
  <progressionPsylink.tones.0>awed and uneasy, aware of power settling into the mind</progressionPsylink.tones.0>
  <progressionPsylink.tones.1>focused and intimate, describing the change from inside the body</progressionPsylink.tones.1>
  <progressionXenotype.label>Gene identity changed</progressionXenotype.label>
  <progressionXenotype.instruction>a gene-identity change; write the bodily and identity shift from the pawn's perspective using only the supplied xenotype and selected gene-theme facts</progressionXenotype.instruction>
  <progressionXenotype.tone>with intimate bodily consequence</progressionXenotype.tone>
  <progressionXenotype.tones.0>changed and watchful, noticing the self becoming unfamiliar</progressionXenotype.tones.0>
  <progressionXenotype.tones.1>visceral and private, focused on what the new body means tonight</progressionXenotype.tones.1>
  <progressionRoyalTitle.label>Royal title changed</progressionRoyalTitle.label>
  <progressionRoyalTitle.instruction>a royal title change; write status, burden, pride, or distance through the new title without explaining faction mechanics</progressionRoyalTitle.instruction>
  <progressionRoyalTitle.tone>with formal weight and personal cost</progressionRoyalTitle.tone>
  <progressionRoyalTitle.tones.0>measured and self-conscious, aware that a title changes how others look</progressionRoyalTitle.tones.0>
  <progressionRoyalTitle.tones.1>quietly burdened, treating rank as both honor and obligation</progressionRoyalTitle.tones.1>
  <progressionTraitGained.label>New trait</progressionTraitGained.label>
  <progressionTraitGained.instruction>a lasting turn in who the pawn is; using only the supplied trait name and its description, write the change from the inside — new urges, reactions, fears, or ways of seeing the world settling into them — as something lived, never as a game trait, stat, number, or mechanic</progressionTraitGained.instruction>
  <progressionTraitGained.tone>with unsettled self-recognition</progressionTraitGained.tone>
  <progressionTraitGained.tones.0>quietly startled, noticing the self think or want something new</progressionTraitGained.tones.0>
  <progressionTraitGained.tones.1>reflective and intimate, tracing where the change shows in ordinary moments</progressionTraitGained.tones.1>
  <progressionOther.label>Progression</progressionOther.label>
  <progressionOther.instruction>a pawn changed in a notable way; write the supplied before-and-after fact plainly and personally</progressionOther.instruction>
  <externalDevTest.label>External test event</externalDevTest.label>
  <externalDevTest.instruction>a test event submitted through the mod integration API; write a short grounded note about an odd but harmless moment</externalDevTest.instruction>
  <externalDevTest.tone>matter-of-fact and mildly puzzled</externalDevTest.tone>

  <!-- Event-coverage pass groups (see EVENT_COVERAGE_PLAN.md) -->
  <raidAnomalyEntities.label>Entity attacks</raidAnomalyEntities.label>
  <raidAnomalyEntities.instruction>inhuman things attacking the colony - write survival under dread, bodies refusing what they see, not a normal battle; never explain what the creatures are</raidAnomalyEntities.instruction>
  <raidAnomalyEntities.instructions.0>inhuman attackers - open on the first wrong detail: shape, gait, wet sound, impossible silence, or a familiar space made unsafe; do not name what they are beyond the supplied label</raidAnomalyEntities.instructions.0>
  <raidAnomalyEntities.instructions.1>inhuman attackers - write the body refusing to accept them as living people: nausea, hair rising, aim shaking, the urge to look away</raidAnomalyEntities.instructions.1>
  <raidAnomalyEntities.instructions.2>inhuman attackers &#8212; keep it survival-close and sensory; use injuries or outcomes only if supplied, and never resolve the horror</raidAnomalyEntities.instructions.2>
  <raidAnomalyEntities.tone>with horror pressing through combat urgency</raidAnomalyEntities.tone>
  <raidAnomalyEntities.tones.0>horrified and sensory, the attackers not registering as people</raidAnomalyEntities.tones.0>
  <raidAnomalyEntities.tones.1>tight and survival-focused, wrongness kept at the edge of the page</raidAnomalyEntities.tones.1>

  <moodeventWeatherHardship.label>Climate hardship</moodeventWeatherHardship.label>
  <moodeventWeatherHardship.instruction>the climate itself turned hostile&#8212;a lasting cold snap, heat wave, or darkened sky. Write the body and the routines coping, not a single dramatic moment</moodeventWeatherHardship.instruction>
  <moodeventWeatherHardship.instructions.0>hostile climate &#8212; write the body first: numb fingers, sweat, shallow breath, clothes that stopped being enough</moodeventWeatherHardship.instructions.0>
  <moodeventWeatherHardship.instructions.1>hostile climate &#8212; write the small adjustments: rationing, moved bedrolls, doors kept shut, crops watched with worry</moodeventWeatherHardship.instructions.1>
  <moodeventWeatherHardship.instructions.2>hostile climate &#8212; let the weather set the day's scale; people and tasks bend around it without a named villain</moodeventWeatherHardship.instructions.2>
  <moodeventWeatherHardship.tone>with worn, enduring patience against the weather</moodeventWeatherHardship.tone>
  <moodeventWeatherHardship.tones.0>weathered and practical, endurance measured in small chores</moodeventWeatherHardship.tones.0>
  <moodeventWeatherHardship.tones.1>quietly worried, the sky deciding what tomorrow costs</moodeventWeatherHardship.tones.1>

  <moodeventStormDanger.label>Sky violence</moodeventStormDanger.label>
  <moodeventStormDanger.instruction>the sky turned violent&#8212;dry lightning, fire, or rain that should not exist. Write sudden danger from above without inventing damage that was not supplied</moodeventStormDanger.instruction>
  <moodeventStormDanger.instructions.0>sky violence &#8212; open on light, sound, or smell: the flash, the crack, the burning air, the first wrong drops</moodeventStormDanger.instructions.0>
  <moodeventStormDanger.instructions.1>sky violence &#8212; write the scramble to react: watching for fires, pulling people indoors, counting what stands exposed</moodeventStormDanger.instructions.1>
  <moodeventStormDanger.instructions.2>sky violence &#8212; if the rain itself is wrong, keep it wrong; unease before explanation, and no invented outcome</moodeventStormDanger.instructions.2>
  <moodeventStormDanger.tone>with sharp alarm under an open sky</moodeventStormDanger.tone>
  <moodeventStormDanger.tones.0>startled and watchful, the sky suddenly an enemy</moodeventStormDanger.tones.0>
  <moodeventStormDanger.tones.1>tense and reactive, danger arriving faster than understanding</moodeventStormDanger.tones.1>

  <mentalbreakViolent.label>Violent breaks</mentalbreakViolent.label>
  <mentalbreakViolent.instruction>the mind breaking outward&#8212;rage that needs a target. Write the heat, the loss of the room, and the moment the body stops asking permission</mentalbreakViolent.instruction>
  <mentalbreakViolent.instructions.0>a violent break &#8212; write the pressure snapping: the last small thing, then heat taking the hands</mentalbreakViolent.instructions.0>
  <mentalbreakViolent.instructions.1>a violent break &#8212; write it through the body: jaw, knuckles, breath, the world reduced to what can be hit</mentalbreakViolent.instructions.1>
  <mentalbreakViolent.instructions.2>a violent break &#8212; if the storm has passed, write the shame and the wreckage the pawn can actually see</mentalbreakViolent.instructions.2>
  <mentalbreakViolent.tone>with red, boiling loss of control</mentalbreakViolent.tone>
  <mentalbreakViolent.tones.0>boiling and immediate, fury ahead of thought</mentalbreakViolent.tones.0>
  <mentalbreakViolent.tones.1>aftermath-heavy, anger cooling into shame</mentalbreakViolent.tones.1>

  <mentalbreakEscape.label>Withdrawal breaks</mentalbreakEscape.label>
  <mentalbreakEscape.instruction>the mind breaking inward&#8212;flight, hiding, or giving up. Write the world becoming too loud and the pull to be anywhere else</mentalbreakEscape.instruction>
  <mentalbreakEscape.instructions.0>an inward break &#8212; write the retreat: feet moving before a decision, the door, the dark, the quiet corner</mentalbreakEscape.instructions.0>
  <mentalbreakEscape.instructions.1>an inward break &#8212; write the weight: everything asked of the pawn at once, and the moment of putting it all down</mentalbreakEscape.instructions.1>
  <mentalbreakEscape.instructions.2>an inward break &#8212; keep the sadness plain and bodily; no dramatic speech, just the leaving</mentalbreakEscape.instructions.2>
  <mentalbreakEscape.tone>with hollow, worn-out flight</mentalbreakEscape.tone>
  <mentalbreakEscape.tones.0>hollow and slow, the world too loud to stay in</mentalbreakEscape.tones.0>
  <mentalbreakEscape.tones.1>numb and drifting, one foot after the other away from people</mentalbreakEscape.tones.1>

  <mentalbreakIndulgent.label>Compulsive breaks</mentalbreakIndulgent.label>
  <mentalbreakIndulgent.instruction>the mind breaking into compulsion&#8212;a binge, a spree, an obsession that feels like relief while it ruins something. Write the hunger and the guilt circling it</mentalbreakIndulgent.instruction>
  <mentalbreakIndulgent.instructions.0>a compulsive break &#8212; write the pull: the promise the compulsion makes, and how good the first taste of it feels</mentalbreakIndulgent.instructions.0>
  <mentalbreakIndulgent.instructions.1>a compulsive break &#8212; write the narrowing: rules, duties, and other people fading behind the one urgent thing</mentalbreakIndulgent.instructions.1>
  <mentalbreakIndulgent.instructions.2>a compulsive break &#8212; let guilt flicker at the edges without stopping anything</mentalbreakIndulgent.instructions.2>
  <mentalbreakIndulgent.tone>with guilty, hungry momentum</mentalbreakIndulgent.tone>
  <mentalbreakIndulgent.tones.0>hungry and rationalizing, relief winning over sense</mentalbreakIndulgent.tones.0>
  <mentalbreakIndulgent.tones.1>sour and compulsive, the urge louder than the shame</mentalbreakIndulgent.tones.1>

  <eventWindowMechCluster.label>Mech cluster</eventWindowMechCluster.label>
  <eventWindowMechCluster.instruction>dormant war machines assembled nearby; write the waiting, the watching, and the planning &#8212; cold mechanical danger that has not moved yet, never an invented battle</eventWindowMechCluster.instruction>
  <eventWindowMechCluster.tone>with cold, patient dread</eventWindowMechCluster.tone>
  <eventWindowMechCluster.tones.0>tense and watchful, danger sitting on the horizon</eventWindowMechCluster.tones.0>
  <eventWindowMechCluster.tones.1>measured and grim, counting defenses against what waits</eventWindowMechCluster.tones.1>

  <observedPitGate.label>Pit gate</observedPitGate.label>
  <observedPitGate.instruction>a pit gate torn open in the colony's ground; write what can be seen and heard at its edge, and never explain what is at the bottom</observedPitGate.instruction>
  <observedPitGate.tone>with dread of what climbs out</observedPitGate.tone>
  <observedPitGate.tones.0>hushed and wary, the ground itself no longer trusted</observedPitGate.tones.0>
  <observedPitGate.tones.1>tight and alert, every sound from below counted</observedPitGate.tones.1>

  <observedFleshmassHeart.label>Fleshmass heart</observedFleshmassHeart.label>
  <observedFleshmassHeart.instruction>a heart of living flesh growing toward the colony; write revulsion and urgency without explaining its biology or inventing a resolved fight</observedFleshmassHeart.instruction>
  <observedFleshmassHeart.tone>with revulsion and urgency</observedFleshmassHeart.tone>
  <observedFleshmassHeart.tones.0>sickened and practical, cutting back what keeps growing</observedFleshmassHeart.tones.0>
  <observedFleshmassHeart.tones.1>unnerved and bodily, the sound of it hard to unhear</observedFleshmassHeart.tones.1>

  <progressionGrowthMoment.label>Growth moment</progressionGrowthMoment.label>
  <progressionGrowthMoment.instruction>a committed childhood growth choice; center identity, changing interests, names, responsibilities, and the qualitative opportunity supplied, without quoting tiers, counts, work lists, or judging the adults who raised the child</progressionGrowthMoment.instruction>
  <progressionGrowthMoment.tone>with formative self-recognition and an uncertain view of who comes next</progressionGrowthMoment.tone>
  <progressionGrowthMoment.tones.0>personal and forward-looking, grounded in the trait or interests that actually changed</progressionGrowthMoment.tones.0>
  <progressionGrowthMoment.tones.1>aware that new choices opened without turning opportunity into a score or inventing who caused it</progressionGrowthMoment.tones.1>

  <progressionMechanitorLifecycle.label>Mechanitor lifecycle</progressionMechanitorLifecycle.label>
  <progressionMechanitorLifecycle.instruction>a mechanitor lifecycle chapter; write from the human controller&apos;s perspective using only the supplied mech, service, combat, or boss-threat facts, never treating bandwidth as emotion and never inventing who struck a final blow</progressionMechanitorLifecycle.instruction>
  <progressionMechanitorLifecycle.tone>with responsibility for minds made into command and consequence</progressionMechanitorLifecycle.tone>
  <progressionMechanitorLifecycle.tones.0>intimate and accountable, centered on the controller&apos;s bond with command</progressionMechanitorLifecycle.tones.0>
  <progressionMechanitorLifecycle.tones.1>technological but personal, keeping exact machines and threats grounded in lived consequence</progressionMechanitorLifecycle.tones.1>

  <biotechFamilyBirth.label>Family birth</biotechFamilyBirth.label>
  <biotechFamilyBirth.instruction>a canonical family birth remembered by an exact adult participant; use only the supplied role and outcome facts, allow mixed fear, grief, exhaustion, relief, or uncertainty, and never assume joy or wanted parenthood</biotechFamilyBirth.instruction>
  <biotechFamilyBirth.tone>with intimate consequence and emotionally honest uncertainty</biotechFamilyBirth.tone>
  <biotechFamilyBirth.tones.0>close to the body and the immediate outcome, without assigning feelings the writer did not supply</biotechFamilyBirth.tones.0>
  <biotechFamilyBirth.tones.1>family-centered but unsentimental, careful about distinct birther, mother, and father roles</biotechFamilyBirth.tones.1>
  <personaWeaponLifecycle.label>Persona weapon bonds</personaWeaponLifecycle.label>
  <personaWeaponLifecycle.instruction>a persona-weapon bond lifecycle edge; use the exact weapon, previous/new bond state, duration, prior bonded pawn, ending cause, and selected structural trait facts supplied; never invent speech, a combat scene, a weapon motive, or a death</personaWeaponLifecycle.instruction>
  <personaWeaponLifecycle.tone>with intimate loyalty, friction, and the unsettling presence of a weapon that remembers</personaWeaponLifecycle.tone>
  <personaWeaponLifecycle.tones.0>intimate and uncanny, treating the bond as a lived relationship without giving the weapon invented dialogue</personaWeaponLifecycle.tones.0>
  <personaWeaponLifecycle.tones.1>close and reflective, grounded in loyalty, absence, return, or finality shown by the exact lifecycle facts</personaWeaponLifecycle.tones.1>
</LanguageData>
