<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Pawn Diary: Vanilla Social Interactions Expanded</name>
  <author>aimmlegate</author>
  <packageId>aimmlegate.pawndiary.adapter.vsie</packageId>
  <modVersion IgnoreIfNoMatchingField="True">0.2.0</modVersion>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <!-- Pawn Diary is a hard dependency: this mod ships only DiaryInteractionGroupDefs, whose C#
       type lives in Pawn Diary's assembly, so those Defs cannot parse without it loaded first.
       Vanilla Social Interactions Expanded is deliberately NOT a hard dependency: every group is
       gated by enableWhenPackageIdsLoaded, so the whole mod sits fully inert (never records, never
       warns) when VSIE is absent, and lights up automatically when it is present. -->
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>aimmlegate.pawndiary.development</packageId>
      <displayName>Pawn Diary</displayName>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>aimmlegate.pawndiary.development</li>
    <li>VanillaExpanded.VanillaSocialInteractionsExpanded</li>
  </loadAfter>
  <description>Teaches Pawn Diary about the new social moments from Vanilla Social Interactions Expanded (VSIE).

With both mods active, VSIE's extra social life shows up in the diary in its own voice instead of being lumped into the generic "other conversation" bucket:
- Venting — one colonist unburdening to another; usually folded into the day's ambient social note, but a charged moment can surface as its own confiding entry.
- Teaching &amp; learning — skill lessons between colonists, gathered into an ambient day-note.
- Discord — a colonist's angry insult at another; recorded with its sting alongside the vanilla "insults and fights" it belongs with (and the social fight it can spark), not as friendly chatter.
- Becoming best friends (VSIE_BestFriend) — recorded as a real relationship milestone, like the vanilla romance milestones.
- VSIE's extra mood thoughts — themed so they read as social afterthoughts rather than generic mood notes.
- Group gatherings — a birthday party or a funeral becomes its own diary entry (from the organizer's point of view), so the colony moment is remembered, not just each colonist's private feeling about it. Birthdays and funerals each have their own on/off toggle in this mod's settings. VSIE's other gatherings (movie night, skygazing, dates, and so on) are left to the mood-thought capture above.

Mostly XML, plus a tiny assembly for the gathering hook. Nothing is written unless VSIE is installed. Requires Pawn Diary. Deployed as a separate RimWorld mod via scripts/deploy-integrations.ps1. (VSIE's venting, teaching, best-friend, and mood-thought entries stay toggleable in Pawn Diary's own Events tab.)</description>
</ModMetaData>
