<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Pawn Diary: Vanilla Social Interactions Expanded</name>
  <author>aimmlegate</author>
  <packageId>aimmlegate.pawndiary.adapter.vsie</packageId>
  <modVersion IgnoreIfNoMatchingField="True">0.2.0</modVersion>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <!-- Pawn Diary is a hard dependency: this mod ships only DiaryInteractionGroupDefs, whose C#
       type lives in Pawn Diary's assembly, so those Defs cannot parse without it loaded first.
       Vanilla Social Interactions Expanded is deliberately NOT a hard dependency: every group is
       gated by enableWhenPackageIdsLoaded, so the whole mod sits fully inert (never records, never
       warns) when VSIE is absent, and lights up automatically when it is present. -->
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>aimmlegate.pawndiary.development</packageId>
      <displayName>Pawn Diary</displayName>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>aimmlegate.pawndiary.development</li>
    <li>VanillaExpanded.VanillaSocialInteractionsExpanded</li>
  </loadAfter>
  <description>Teaches Pawn Diary the social life added by Vanilla Social Interactions Expanded, so it reaches the diary in its own voice instead of the generic "other conversation" bucket.

- Venting and teaching are woven into the day's social notes; a truly charged confession can stand alone.
- An angry insult keeps its sting, recorded next to vanilla insults and fights.
- Becoming best friends is a real relationship milestone.
- A birthday party or a funeral becomes its own diary entry, so the colony remembers the moment itself (each has its own toggle in this mod's settings).
- VSIE's extra moods read as afterthoughts of real encounters, not stray notes.

Requires Pawn Diary. Fully inert until VSIE is active — safe to keep installed either way.

———

Учит Pawn Diary социальной жизни из Vanilla Social Interactions Expanded: она попадает в дневник своим голосом, а не общей строкой «просто поговорили».

- Наболевшее и наставничество вплетаются в социальные заметки дня; по-настоящему сильная исповедь может стать отдельной записью.
- Злая насмешка сохраняет своё жало и встаёт рядом с обычными оскорблениями и драками.
- Новая лучшая дружба — настоящая веха отношений.
- День рождения или похороны становятся отдельной записью: поселение помнит само событие (у каждого — свой переключатель в настройках мода).
- Дополнительные настроения VSIE читаются как отголоски живых встреч, а не случайные заметки.

Требуется Pawn Diary. Пока VSIE не активен, мод полностью бездействует — держать его установленным безопасно в любом случае.</description>
</ModMetaData>
