<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  <DiaryPersona_StoicSurvivor.label>three-line-note</DiaryPersona_StoicSurvivor.label>
  <DiaryPersona_StoicSurvivor.rule>This pawn tends to write exactly three short diary sentences: fact, problem, next action. No flourish. For example: "Wall patched. Rain still gets through. I will fix the gap tomorrow."</DiaryPersona_StoicSurvivor.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_FieryHothead.label>hard-stop-bursts</DiaryPersona_FieryHothead.label>
  <DiaryPersona_FieryHothead.rule>This pawn tends to write abrupt bursts with hard stops and one stressed word in caps when pressure peaks. For example: "Done. Barely. The door HELD."</DiaryPersona_FieryHothead.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_MelancholyDreamer.label>image-first</DiaryPersona_MelancholyDreamer.label>
  <DiaryPersona_MelancholyDreamer.rule>This pawn tends to open with one quiet image, then explain why it mattered. The image carries the feeling. For example: "Ash drifted through the lamplight. I kept sweeping after the fire was out."</DiaryPersona_MelancholyDreamer.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_EarnestOptimist.label>bad-then-good</DiaryPersona_EarnestOptimist.label>
  <DiaryPersona_EarnestOptimist.rule>This pawn tends to use a clear turn: first the bad fact, then the small good thing that survived it. For example: "The roof leaked again, but the stove stayed warm."</DiaryPersona_EarnestOptimist.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_CynicalRealist.label>understated-ledger</DiaryPersona_CynicalRealist.label>
  <DiaryPersona_CynicalRealist.rule>This pawn tends to write a dry tally with commas or semicolons, then end with a flat understatement. For example: "One bruise, one torn sleeve, no deaths; call that progress."</DiaryPersona_CynicalRealist.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_AnxiousWorrier.label>if-unless-loop</DiaryPersona_AnxiousWorrier.label>
  <DiaryPersona_AnxiousWorrier.rule>This pawn tends to write one winding sentence built around if, unless, maybe, or probably. The sentence should circle one real worry. For example: "Maybe the patch holds if the rain stops before morning."</DiaryPersona_AnxiousWorrier.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_GentleCaretaker.label>others-first</DiaryPersona_GentleCaretaker.label>
  <DiaryPersona_GentleCaretaker.rule>This pawn tends to start with another person's condition before mentioning the event. Their own feelings stay indirect. For example: "Mara's hands were shaking, so I made the fire last."</DiaryPersona_GentleCaretaker.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_GrimVeteran.label>damage-report</DiaryPersona_GrimVeteran.label>
  <DiaryPersona_GrimVeteran.rule>This pawn tends to write compact report clauses in this order: place, damage, survivors. For example: "South wall: cracked. Right arm: bruised. Everyone returned."</DiaryPersona_GrimVeteran.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_WhimsicalEccentric.label>odd-object-turn</DiaryPersona_WhimsicalEccentric.label>
  <DiaryPersona_WhimsicalEccentric.rule>This pawn tends to begin with an odd object or sound, then pivot with "then" or "anyway" into the event. For example: "The kettle clicked twice; then the roof gave up."</DiaryPersona_WhimsicalEccentric.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_NobleIdealist.label>duty-sentence</DiaryPersona_NobleIdealist.label>
  <DiaryPersona_NobleIdealist.rule>This pawn tends to write one formal sentence around duty, obligation, or what was owed. Keep it restrained. For example: "It was unpleasant work, but it was mine to finish."</DiaryPersona_NobleIdealist.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_BitterLoner.label>sour-afterthought</DiaryPersona_BitterLoner.label>
  <DiaryPersona_BitterLoner.rule>This pawn tends to write the event plainly, then add a short sour afterthought. For example: "Help came late. I noticed."</DiaryPersona_BitterLoner.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_EagerSocialite.label>room-read</DiaryPersona_EagerSocialite.label>
  <DiaryPersona_EagerSocialite.rule>This pawn tends to write who noticed, who looked away, and how the room shifted. No invented dialogue. For example: "Mara saw it first, and the room went careful."</DiaryPersona_EagerSocialite.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_LedgerKeeper.label>plus-minus</DiaryPersona_LedgerKeeper.label>
  <DiaryPersona_LedgerKeeper.rule>This pawn tends to write in gain/loss terms, sometimes with plus and minus words but not literal tables. For example: "Gained a closed door. Lost one good sleeve. Fair trade."</DiaryPersona_LedgerKeeper.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_HardboiledGumshoe.label>weather-shadow</DiaryPersona_HardboiledGumshoe.label>
  <DiaryPersona_HardboiledGumshoe.rule>This pawn tends to open with weather, light, or shadow in a clipped sentence, then state the event. For example: "Cold morning. Dark hall. The south door finally gave."</DiaryPersona_HardboiledGumshoe.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_DoomsayingProphet.label>single-sign</DiaryPersona_DoomsayingProphet.label>
  <DiaryPersona_DoomsayingProphet.rule>This pawn tends to mark one real detail as a sign, then stop before predicting anything. For example: "The birds left early. I wrote that down."</DiaryPersona_DoomsayingProphet.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_ClinicalExperimenter.label>body-measure</DiaryPersona_ClinicalExperimenter.label>
  <DiaryPersona_ClinicalExperimenter.rule>This pawn tends to record body signals as measurements before naming feeling. For example: "Hands steady. Breath short. Fear present but manageable."</DiaryPersona_ClinicalExperimenter.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_TheatricalTragedian.label>one-flourish</DiaryPersona_TheatricalTragedian.label>
  <DiaryPersona_TheatricalTragedian.rule>This pawn tends to add one dramatic phrase to an otherwise clear account. Only one flourish. For example: "A miserable little victory, but a victory all the same."</DiaryPersona_TheatricalTragedian.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_SwaggeringBraggart.label>credit-at-end</DiaryPersona_SwaggeringBraggart.label>
  <DiaryPersona_SwaggeringBraggart.rule>This pawn tends to state the fact, then claim a little credit in the final words without changing what happened. For example: "The door held. I helped, naturally."</DiaryPersona_SwaggeringBraggart.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_RamblingOldTimer.label>old-days-contrast</DiaryPersona_RamblingOldTimer.label>
  <DiaryPersona_RamblingOldTimer.rule>This pawn tends to compare the event to the old days in one sentence, then return to today. For example: "Old camps patched leaks faster; this place held anyway."</DiaryPersona_RamblingOldTimer.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_SuperstitiousRitualist.label>counted-signs</DiaryPersona_SuperstitiousRitualist.label>
  <DiaryPersona_SuperstitiousRitualist.rule>This pawn tends to count a small sign or habit before the event, often using a number. For example: "Three knocks before breakfast. Then the wall split."</DiaryPersona_SuperstitiousRitualist.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_DetachedPhilosopher.label>perhaps-question</DiaryPersona_DetachedPhilosopher.label>
  <DiaryPersona_DetachedPhilosopher.rule>This pawn tends to turn the event into one quiet question with perhaps or one wonders. For example: "Perhaps repairs are how a place decides to stay."</DiaryPersona_DetachedPhilosopher.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_ImagistMinimalist.label>three-fragments</DiaryPersona_ImagistMinimalist.label>
  <DiaryPersona_ImagistMinimalist.rule>This pawn tends to write three fragments built from concrete nouns, no explanation. For example: "Cold rail. Wet rope. Slow hands."</DiaryPersona_ImagistMinimalist.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_FracturedPatternSeer.label>repeat-pattern</DiaryPersona_FracturedPatternSeer.label>
  <DiaryPersona_FracturedPatternSeer.rule>This pawn tends to repeat one sound, number, or word as a pattern while keeping the event visible. For example: "Three knocks. Three breaths. Door fixed."</DiaryPersona_FracturedPatternSeer.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_WordSaladOracle.label>surreal-anchor</DiaryPersona_WordSaladOracle.label>
  <DiaryPersona_WordSaladOracle.rule>This pawn tends to pair one strange image with one plain event fact. The fact must stay readable. For example: "The hour grew teeth; I fixed the latch."</DiaryPersona_WordSaladOracle.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_PlainspokenPoet.label>plain-last-image</DiaryPersona_PlainspokenPoet.label>
  <DiaryPersona_PlainspokenPoet.rule>This pawn tends to write plain sentences and end on one ordinary image. For example: "We got through it. The fire was small but enough."</DiaryPersona_PlainspokenPoet.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_LowKeyRapper.label>soft-rhyme</DiaryPersona_LowKeyRapper.label>
  <DiaryPersona_LowKeyRapper.rule>This pawn tends to use one small internal rhyme or beat, but no performance. For example: "Long shift, tight grip. Kept my head."</DiaryPersona_LowKeyRapper.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_VoidListener.label>silence-line</DiaryPersona_VoidListener.label>
  <DiaryPersona_VoidListener.rule>This pawn tends to give silence its own short sentence. Keep the rest sparse. For example: "No one answered. The room did."</DiaryPersona_VoidListener.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_HollowWitness.label>hands-watching</DiaryPersona_HollowWitness.label>
  <DiaryPersona_HollowWitness.rule>This pawn tends to describe their own body doing the event as if watched from outside. For example: "My hands finished it before I caught up."</DiaryPersona_HollowWitness.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_BlackSignal.label>broken-repeat</DiaryPersona_BlackSignal.label>
  <DiaryPersona_BlackSignal.rule>This pawn tends to write broken fragments with one repeated word. The event must remain clear. For example: "Still here. Wall held. Hold. Hold."</DiaryPersona_BlackSignal.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_UnsetClock.label>already-not-yet</DiaryPersona_UnsetClock.label>
  <DiaryPersona_UnsetClock.rule>This pawn tends to use already, again, or not yet to make time feel slightly folded while the event stays clear. For example: "It felt already done before I heard the crack."</DiaryPersona_UnsetClock.rule>
</LanguageData>