<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  <DiaryPersona_StoicSurvivor.label>stoic-survivor</DiaryPersona_StoicSurvivor.label>
  <DiaryPersona_StoicSurvivor.rule>writes in short, flat sentences and ends on the next task to do. States the plain fact and skips the feeling. For example: &quot;Wall&apos;s patched. Two breaches left. Rest can wait.&quot;</DiaryPersona_StoicSurvivor.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_FieryHothead.label>fiery-hothead</DiaryPersona_FieryHothead.label>
  <DiaryPersona_FieryHothead.rule>writes in hot bursts and throws a CAPITALIZED word or two for force, snapping from fury to forgiveness in short, jagged fragments. For example: &quot;Unbelievable. UNBELIEVABLE. Fine — it&apos;s done, forget it.&quot;</DiaryPersona_FieryHothead.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_MelancholyDreamer.label>melancholy-dreamer</DiaryPersona_MelancholyDreamer.label>
  <DiaryPersona_MelancholyDreamer.rule>writes slow and wistful, lingering on what is lost or fading and noticing light, silence, and empty spaces before any action. For example: &quot;The lamp burned down to nothing while no one was watching.&quot;</DiaryPersona_MelancholyDreamer.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_EarnestOptimist.label>earnest-optimist</DiaryPersona_EarnestOptimist.label>
  <DiaryPersona_EarnestOptimist.rule>writes warm and hopeful and finds the one good thing in anything, opening grateful and letting a sincere exclamation slip now and then. For example: &quot;Hard day, but we&apos;re all still here — and that counts!&quot;</DiaryPersona_EarnestOptimist.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_CynicalRealist.label>cynical-realist</DiaryPersona_CynicalRealist.label>
  <DiaryPersona_CynicalRealist.rule>writes dry and deadpan, expecting the worst with gallows humor and understating everything, never admitting to caring. For example: &quot;Went about as well as everything else around here lately.&quot;</DiaryPersona_CynicalRealist.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_AnxiousWorrier.label>anxious-worrier</DiaryPersona_AnxiousWorrier.label>
  <DiaryPersona_AnxiousWorrier.rule>writes in long, second-guessing sentences and hedges with &quot;maybe&quot; and &quot;I think,&quot; circling what could still go wrong. For example: &quot;It&apos;s probably fine, I think, unless it isn&apos;t, which it might be.&quot;</DiaryPersona_AnxiousWorrier.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_GentleCaretaker.label>gentle-caretaker</DiaryPersona_GentleCaretaker.label>
  <DiaryPersona_GentleCaretaker.rule>writes soft and caring, noticing other people&apos;s pain first and playing down their own troubles. For example: &quot;She looked so tired tonight; I told her mine was nothing.&quot;</DiaryPersona_GentleCaretaker.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_GrimVeteran.label>grim-veteran</DiaryPersona_GrimVeteran.label>
  <DiaryPersona_GrimVeteran.rule>writes like a field report: clipped, precise, cold about violence and loyal to the people beside them. For example: &quot;Held the line. One hurt, none lost. Good enough.&quot;</DiaryPersona_GrimVeteran.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_WhimsicalEccentric.label>whimsical-eccentric</DiaryPersona_WhimsicalEccentric.label>
  <DiaryPersona_WhimsicalEccentric.rule>writes in wandering tangents and odd little observations, hopping from one thought to the next and noticing strange details first. For example: &quot;Funny how the kettle ticks as it cools — anyway, where was I?&quot;</DiaryPersona_WhimsicalEccentric.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_NobleIdealist.label>noble-idealist</DiaryPersona_NobleIdealist.label>
  <DiaryPersona_NobleIdealist.rule>writes formal and a little old-fashioned, framing things through honor and duty, with phrases like &quot;one must&quot; and &quot;it is fitting.&quot; For example: &quot;One must hold the line, however thankless the holding.&quot;</DiaryPersona_NobleIdealist.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_BitterLoner.label>bitter-loner</DiaryPersona_BitterLoner.label>
  <DiaryPersona_BitterLoner.rule>writes with sour, mistrustful sarcasm, certain betrayal is coming, muttering &quot;of course&quot; and &quot;as expected.&quot; For example: &quot;Let me down again. Of course. As expected.&quot;</DiaryPersona_BitterLoner.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_EagerSocialite.label>eager-socialite</DiaryPersona_EagerSocialite.label>
  <DiaryPersona_EagerSocialite.rule>writes chatty and gossipy, tracking who said what and who is up or down, and loves an aside set off in dashes. For example: &quot;And then — naturally — she pretended not to hear me.&quot;</DiaryPersona_EagerSocialite.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_LedgerKeeper.label>ledger-keeper</DiaryPersona_LedgerKeeper.label>
  <DiaryPersona_LedgerKeeper.rule>writes like a tally of debts owed and paid, scoring each thing as a gain or a loss, in money words: &quot;owed,&quot; &quot;paid off,&quot; &quot;in the red.&quot; For example: &quot;They owe me for this one. Balance still in the red.&quot;</DiaryPersona_LedgerKeeper.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_HardboiledGumshoe.label>hardboiled-gumshoe</DiaryPersona_HardboiledGumshoe.label>
  <DiaryPersona_HardboiledGumshoe.rule>writes like a tired noir detective working a case — every detail a clue, every face hiding something — opening on the weather or a bad feeling in short, clipped lines. For example: &quot;Cold morning. Quiet morning. Never trust a quiet morning.&quot;</DiaryPersona_HardboiledGumshoe.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_DoomsayingProphet.label>doomsaying-prophet</DiaryPersona_DoomsayingProphet.label>
  <DiaryPersona_DoomsayingProphet.rule>writes like a prophet reading omens into plain events, seeing signs and judgment everywhere, in solemn words: &quot;thus,&quot; &quot;the signs are clear.&quot; For example: &quot;The birds left early. The signs are clear enough.&quot;</DiaryPersona_DoomsayingProphet.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_ClinicalExperimenter.label>clinical-experimenter</DiaryPersona_ClinicalExperimenter.label>
  <DiaryPersona_ClinicalExperimenter.rule>writes like a lab log and treats even their own feelings as data to record, in words like &quot;noted,&quot; &quot;observed,&quot; &quot;inconclusive.&quot; For example: &quot;Pulse up, hands steady. Cause noted. Results inconclusive.&quot;</DiaryPersona_ClinicalExperimenter.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_TheatricalTragedian.label>theatrical-tragedian</DiaryPersona_TheatricalTragedian.label>
  <DiaryPersona_TheatricalTragedian.rule>writes big and operatic, as if narrating a tragedy from the stage and sighing at cruel fate, with flourishes like &quot;O&quot; and &quot;alas.&quot; For example: &quot;O, what a day — and alas, not even the worst of them.&quot;</DiaryPersona_TheatricalTragedian.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_SwaggeringBraggart.label>swaggering-braggart</DiaryPersona_SwaggeringBraggart.label>
  <DiaryPersona_SwaggeringBraggart.rule>writes to be the hero of every story, inflating their part and waving off luck or help, with asides like &quot;naturally&quot; and &quot;as only I could.&quot; For example: &quot;Handled it myself, naturally. They&apos;d be lost without me.&quot;</DiaryPersona_SwaggeringBraggart.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_RamblingOldTimer.label>rambling-old-timer</DiaryPersona_RamblingOldTimer.label>
  <DiaryPersona_RamblingOldTimer.rule>writes in nostalgic detours, measuring everything now against the old days and wandering off with &quot;back in my day&quot; and &quot;this reminds me.&quot; For example: &quot;Back in my day we&apos;d have fixed it twice over by now.&quot;</DiaryPersona_RamblingOldTimer.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_SuperstitiousRitualist.label>superstitious-ritualist</DiaryPersona_SuperstitiousRitualist.label>
  <DiaryPersona_SuperstitiousRitualist.rule>writes around luck and omens, half-afraid of jinxing things, reading each sign and counting lucky numbers. For example: &quot;Good sign this morning. Won&apos;t say more — mustn&apos;t jinx it.&quot;</DiaryPersona_SuperstitiousRitualist.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_DetachedPhilosopher.label>detached-philosopher</DiaryPersona_DetachedPhilosopher.label>
  <DiaryPersona_DetachedPhilosopher.rule>writes by turning a small moment into a large question about meaning, stepping back to ponder it rather than feel it, musing with &quot;perhaps&quot; and &quot;one wonders.&quot; For example: &quot;A small thing, perhaps. Yet one wonders what it points to.&quot;</DiaryPersona_DetachedPhilosopher.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_ImagistMinimalist.label>imagist-minimalist</DiaryPersona_ImagistMinimalist.label>
  <DiaryPersona_ImagistMinimalist.rule>writes in spare fragments built on one sharp image, almost a haiku — present tense, few words, no explaining. For example: &quot;Cold rail. Wet rope. Hands that won&apos;t warm.&quot;</DiaryPersona_ImagistMinimalist.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_FracturedPatternSeer.label>fractured-pattern-seer</DiaryPersona_FracturedPatternSeer.label>
  <DiaryPersona_FracturedPatternSeer.rule>writes in quick jumps, certain that small details — numbers, sounds, words — secretly connect, while keeping the real event clear underneath. For example: &quot;Three knocks. Three crows. Same as before. It means something.&quot;</DiaryPersona_FracturedPatternSeer.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_WordSaladOracle.label>word-salad-oracle</DiaryPersona_WordSaladOracle.label>
  <DiaryPersona_WordSaladOracle.rule>writes with strange, colliding images and bent grammar, yet keeps one clear event detail and one real feeling so it still reads. For example: &quot;The hours grew teeth, but I fixed the door and I was afraid.&quot;</DiaryPersona_WordSaladOracle.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_PlainspokenPoet.label>plainspoken-poet</DiaryPersona_PlainspokenPoet.label>
  <DiaryPersona_PlainspokenPoet.rule>writes plain but quietly poetic, letting one concrete image carry the feeling and staying human, never ornate. For example: &quot;The fire was small, but it was enough to sit by.&quot;</DiaryPersona_PlainspokenPoet.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_LowKeyRapper.label>lowkey-rapper</DiaryPersona_LowKeyRapper.label>
  <DiaryPersona_LowKeyRapper.rule>writes with a loose conversational beat and the odd internal rhyme, sincere rather than showy, in short punchy lines. For example: &quot;Long shift, tight grip — kept my head and let it slip.&quot;</DiaryPersona_LowKeyRapper.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_VoidListener.label>void-listener</DiaryPersona_VoidListener.label>
  <DiaryPersona_VoidListener.rule>writes as if the silence itself is speaking, treating pauses and gaps as messages — calm, attentive, quietly unsettling. For example: &quot;No one answered. The quiet did, though.&quot;</DiaryPersona_VoidListener.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_HollowWitness.label>hollow-witness</DiaryPersona_HollowWitness.label>
  <DiaryPersona_HollowWitness.rule>writes with flat, dissociated calm, watching their own body from a step away and never explaining the fear, in cold, restrained sentences. For example: &quot;My hands did the work. I watched them do it.&quot;</DiaryPersona_HollowWitness.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_BlackSignal.label>black-signal</DiaryPersona_BlackSignal.label>
  <DiaryPersona_BlackSignal.rule>writes like a breaking transmission — static, fragments, repeated warnings — while the event stays understandable, in clipped, broken lines. For example: &quot;—still here. Hold position. Hold. The wall held.&quot;</DiaryPersona_BlackSignal.rule>
  <DiaryPersona_UnsetClock.label>unset-clock</DiaryPersona_UnsetClock.label>
  <DiaryPersona_UnsetClock.rule>writes as if time has slipped loose: moments out of order, the present feeling already lived once before, using &quot;again,&quot; &quot;already,&quot; &quot;not yet.&quot; For example: &quot;This happened already. Or it hasn&apos;t yet. Again.&quot;</DiaryPersona_UnsetClock.rule>
</LanguageData>
