<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>PawnDiary: RimTalk bridge</name>
  <author>aimmlegate</author>
  <packageId>aimmlegate.pawndiary.rimtalkbridge</packageId>
  <modVersion IgnoreIfNoMatchingField="True">0.2.0</modVersion>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>aimmlegate.pawndiary.development</packageId>
      <displayName>Pawn Diary</displayName>
    </li>
    <li>
      <packageId>cj.rimtalk</packageId>
      <displayName>RimTalk</displayName>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>aimmlegate.pawndiary.development</li>
    <li>cj.rimtalk</li>
  </loadAfter>
  <description>Bridges Pawn Diary and RimTalk so a colonist's chat and their diary share one inner life.

Pick an integration level in the mod settings:
- Off — nothing flows between the two mods.
- Shared context (default) — pawns "remember" their diary in conversation: recent diary memories are injected into RimTalk's chat prompts, and each pawn's RimTalk persona is shown to the diary as context. When two colonists talk, the past diary moments they share become "previous interactions" in the conversation. You can also opt in to a short, curated line about the colony's current situation (a raid, harsh weather, an eerie presence, an open quest). Nothing is written from chat.
- Shared context + conversations — additionally, important RimTalk conversations (arguments, kindness, urgent news, long exchanges) become diary entries for both participants. Ordinary chatter stays in Pawn Diary's own ambient day-note, not spammed as individual entries.

Advanced options include toggles and counts for the shared-memory and colony-situation context, a persona-led diary voice (experimental), routing conversation entries through RimTalk's own AI provider, and per-day/per-pair throttles.

Requires Pawn Diary and RimTalk. Installs the core "RimTalk conversations" compatibility group in Pawn Diary automatically. Deployed as a separate RimWorld mod via scripts/deploy-integrations.ps1.</description>
</ModMetaData>
