<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Pawn Diary: 1-2-3 Personalities</name>
  <author>aimmlegate</author>
  <packageId>aimmlegate.pawndiary.adapter.personalities123</packageId>
  <modVersion IgnoreIfNoMatchingField="True">0.1.0</modVersion>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <!-- Both hard dependencies are load-order + assembly-resolution requirements, not just hints:
       - Pawn Diary owns the DiaryInteractionGroupDef type this mod's Defs are, and the integration API
         this mod's assembly calls.
       - 1-2-3 Personalities M1 owns SP_Module1.dll, which this mod's assembly references to read each
         colonist's Enneagram. Without M1 the assembly would fail to resolve, so it is a real dependency.
       Module 2 (the ThoughtDef/InteractionDef expansion) is OPTIONAL: it is only referenced by string
       package-id in XML, so the module-2 groups sit inert until it is installed. -->
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>aimmlegate.pawndiary.development</packageId>
      <displayName>Pawn Diary</displayName>
    </li>
    <li>
      <packageId>hahkethomemah.simplepersonalities</packageId>
      <displayName>1-2-3 Personalities M1</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2527258500</steamWorkshopUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>aimmlegate.pawndiary.development</li>
    <li>hahkethomemah.simplepersonalities</li>
    <li>hahkethomemah.simplepersonalities.module2</li>
  </loadAfter>
  <description>Lets a colonist's 1-2-3 Personalities character shape their Pawn Diary.

- Personality on the page: Module 2's compatibility moments and personality moods are written in their own voice — how it feels to click with someone, or grate on them. Module 2 is optional; without it this part simply sleeps.
- Personality as diary voice: one setting turns each colonist's Enneagram into their diary psychotype — pick the closest built-in one, fill their editable outlook with ready-made text, or let your language model write it (experimental). You can still edit or clear the result on any pawn, and it follows personality changes.

1-2-3 Personalities decides who the pawn is; Pawn Diary decides how they write. Nothing is ever written back into 1-2-3 Personalities.

Requires Pawn Diary and 1-2-3 Personalities M1; Module 2 recommended.

———

Характер из 1-2-3 Personalities начинает влиять на дневник поселенца в Pawn Diary.

- Характер на странице: моменты совместимости и настроения характера из Module 2 записываются своим голосом — легко ли человеку рядом с собеседником или тот его раздражает. Module 2 не обязателен; без него эта часть просто спит.
- Характер как голос дневника: одна настройка превращает эннеаграмму поселенца в его психотип — подобрать ближайший встроенный, заполнить редактируемый взгляд готовым текстом или доверить это вашей языковой модели (экспериментально). Результат можно править и стирать у любого поселенца, а при смене характера он обновляется сам.

1-2-3 Personalities решает, кто этот поселенец; Pawn Diary — как он пишет. Обратно в 1-2-3 Personalities ничего не записывается.

Требуются Pawn Diary и 1-2-3 Personalities M1; Module 2 желателен.</description>
</ModMetaData>
