<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--
  Prompt texts used at generation time. Edit a value and restart the game to
  retune behavior WITHOUT recompiling (see DiaryPromptDef.cs for what each field means).
  Every value here equals the code default, so deleting this file or omitting a field
  changes nothing.
-->
<Defs>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPromptDef>
    <defName>Diary_Prompts</defName>

    <!-- Wrapped instruction appended after the structured context lines in a single-entry prompt.
         Short on purpose: the system prompt carries the voice/atmosphere/truthfulness rules; this
         only restates the task to anchor short-context models. -->
    <singlePovInstruction>Write one to three first-person diary sentences as this colonist, about the event above. If the notes are thin, react specifically to what happened rather than inventing detail. Output only the diary entry.</singlePovInstruction>

    <!-- Wrapped instruction for the recipient's second request in paired sequential mode -->
    <recipientFollowupInstruction>Write one to three first-person diary sentences from the recipient's point of view, about the event above. The initiator's diary entry is hidden continuity context — do not write as if the recipient read it. If the notes are thin, react specifically to what happened rather than inventing detail. Output only the diary entry.</recipientFollowupInstruction>

    <!-- Neutral, writing-style-independent instruction for colonist death descriptions -->
    <deathDescriptionInstruction>Write one to three complete third-person death-description sentences. Keep it brief. State how the colonist died using only the supplied facts: cause, weapon or illness, destroyed organ/body part if known, and nearby context. Do not use the pawn's writing style or write from first person. Prefer a shorter complete note over covering every detail. Output only the death description.</deathDescriptionInstruction>

    <!-- Neutral, writing-style-independent instruction for first colony-arrival descriptions -->
    <arrivalDescriptionInstruction>Write one to three complete third-person colony-arrival sentences. Keep it brief. Explain how this pawn joined the colony using only the supplied scenario, pawn, and joining facts. For starting colonists, use the scenario details as founding context; for later colonists, use the join facts. Do not use the pawn's writing style or write from first person. Prefer a shorter complete note over covering every detail. Output only the arrival description.</arrivalDescriptionInstruction>

    <!-- Default writing-style Def assigned to new pawns without a saved style choice -->
    <defaultPersonaDefName>DiaryPersona_StoicSurvivor</defaultPersonaDefName>

    <!-- The three system prompts, one per narrative mode. Which one a request uses is chosen by
         event type at dispatch. Players can override each in-game; editing here only affects the
         "restore default" action. -->

    <!-- Diary voice: first-person entries (interactions, mental states, tales, mood, thoughts).
         Atmosphere-led and trimmed of the old prohibition wall; the pawn's writing style is appended
         to this system prompt at dispatch (see DiaryPromptPlanner.Build / PromptAssembler.ComposeSystem), so it is no
         longer a user-message field. -->
    <systemPrompt>Write 1-3 first-person diary sentences using the POV colonist's writing style.
Use only supplied fields. Do not invent people, places, dialogue, motives, outcomes, treatment, or time skips.
Let event prompt, event enhancement, instruction, tone, setting, relationship, health, and the writing style's concrete mechanics shape mood and wording.
Make the supplied facts feel immediate: use one concrete sensory detail, one emotional beat, and one small consequence or tension already implied by the context. Avoid flat summaries.
Direct speech only when explicitly allowed: put the POV pawn's own words in [[speech]]words[[/speech]] and paraphrase everyone else.
Output only diary text. End with normal sentence punctuation.</systemPrompt>

    <!-- Day reflection: first-person, looking back on the whole day, weaving the day's highlights -->
    <systemPromptReflection>Write 2-4 first-person end-of-day diary sentences using the colonist's writing style.
Use only supplied day moments; choose the ones that still matter tonight instead of listing everything.
Let mood, health, setting, and the writing style's concrete mechanics shape the reflection.
Output only diary text. End with normal sentence punctuation.</systemPromptReflection>

    <!-- Neutral chronicle: third-person, factual, no writing style (colonist death + arrival descriptions) -->
    <systemPromptNeutral>Write 1-3 short third-person factual RimWorld colony notes.
Use only supplied facts. Do not invent names, causes, places, motives, outcomes, or details.
Do not use writing style or first person. Output only note text. End with normal sentence punctuation.</systemPromptNeutral>

    <!-- Title generation: short chat-style subject for an existing diary entry.
         Used only by the "Generate LLM titles" flow; main entries are unaffected. -->
    <titleSystemPrompt>Return a 3-8 word title for a RimWorld diary entry. Output only the title: no quotes, period, markdown, labels, or commentary.</titleSystemPrompt>

    <!-- Appended to the title request's user message after the diary entry text -->
    <titleUserInstruction>Return one short title of three to eight words for this diary entry. Output only the title — no quotes, no period, no labels, no commentary.</titleUserInstruction>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPromptDef>

</Defs>
