<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--
  Event prompt policy. These Defs are the first layer of event-specific prompt control:
  `prompt` names what kind of source the LLM is writing from, and `enhancement` adds source-level
  constraints. Optional `forcedModel` is a raw configured API model id to try first for that event
  source; blank or unknown values are ignored. Narrower flavor still comes from
  DiaryInteractionGroupDef.instruction/tone.

  Compatibility XML can add a new DiaryEventPromptDef without C# code. Runtime tries keys in this
  order and uses the first loaded Def: exact source defName, matched DiaryInteractionGroupDef.defName,
  domain classifier key, then broad event domain (Interaction/Raid/Thought/etc.). Set <eventType> to
  that key, or use the key itself as <defName> when no separate label is needed. Fields resolve
  independently, so a specific Def can set only <forcedModel>, only <enhancement>, or only <prompt>
  and inherit blank fields from the next broader loaded policy.
-->
<Defs>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_Interaction</defName>
    <label>social interaction</label>
    <eventType>Interaction</eventType>
    <prompt>Write a direct social interaction between pawns from the POV pawn's side of the moment.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Make the exchange feel live in the room: a look, pause, flinch, heat, or silence. Keep it tied to the supplied social text; do not add unstated history or dialogue.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_MentalState</defName>
    <label>mental state</label>
    <eventType>MentalState</eventType>
    <prompt>Write a mental-state event as immediate pressure on thought, impulse, and action.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Write with pressure and unstable momentum: thought, impulse, body, then action. Stay inside the named state and observed behavior; do not diagnose beyond supplied facts.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_Tale</defName>
    <label>tale</label>
    <eventType>Tale</eventType>
    <prompt>Write a notable non-social RimWorld tale as something the pawn lived through or remembers.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Find the dramatic pressure in the tale facts: danger, pride, shame, relief, damage, or aftermath. Do not turn the entry into ordinary social chatter.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_MoodEvent</defName>
    <label>mood event</label>
    <eventType>MoodEvent</eventType>
    <prompt>Write a colony-wide mood event through how it touches this pawn.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Show the condition pressing on the pawn's senses or nerves rather than explaining game mechanics; keep the condition's scope clear.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_Thought</defName>
    <label>thought</label>
    <eventType>Thought</eventType>
    <prompt>Write a temporary thought or mood memory as inner pressure, relief, or irritation.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Make the thought bite, comfort, itch, or linger in the pawn's mind. Treat it as internal context, not as a new external event unless the facts say so.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_Inspiration</defName>
    <label>inspiration</label>
    <eventType>Inspiration</eventType>
    <prompt>Write inspiration as sudden useful clarity catching in the pawn's mind.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Make the clarity feel electric and actionable: a sudden plan, urge, or confidence. Focus on what the pawn wants to do next; do not invent success.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_Romance</defName>
    <label>romance</label>
    <eventType>Romance</eventType>
    <prompt>Write a relationship milestone as an emotional change between the two people.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Make the changed bond feel risky and personal: hope, embarrassment, ache, relief, or dread. Do not backfill a conversation or private scene.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_Work</defName>
    <label>work</label>
    <eventType>Work</eventType>
    <prompt>Write sampled colony work as a concrete moment in the pawn's labor.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Use tactile work detail: weight, heat, dirt, rhythm, tools, mistakes, or satisfaction. Let passion, strain, or dread come only from supplied fields.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_Hediff</defName>
    <label>health condition</label>
    <eventType>Hediff</eventType>
    <prompt>Write a health-condition event through the pawn's body and mood.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Make the body unavoidable: pain, weakness, breath, fever, hunger, balance, or fear. Do not invent treatment, diagnosis, or recovery.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_Raid</defName>
    <label>raid</label>
    <eventType>Raid</eventType>
    <prompt>Write a raid, drop-pod attack, or infestation from the pawn's immediate experience of danger.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Use the supplied raid fields, especially arrival mode and strategy. For ordinary raids, favor warning, preparation, first sight, and anticipation of the fight; for drop pods or infestations, write sudden contact already inside or under the colony. Keep every detail grounded and do not invent battle outcomes.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_Quest</defName>
    <label>quest</label>
    <eventType>Quest</eventType>
    <prompt>Write a quest lifecycle event as a colony promise, shared resolution, or shared loss.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Make the quest feel personal without assigning the work to this pawn alone. Use the lifecycle signal and supplied quest facts; for completed or failed quests, frame the outcome as the colony's common effort, relief, regret, or cost unless supplied facts explicitly say otherwise. Do not copy the quest name verbatim into the diary line, and do not invent rewards, blame, or consequences.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_Ritual</defName>
    <label>ritual</label>
    <eventType>Ritual</eventType>
    <prompt>Write a finished Ideology ritual from the pawn's assigned place in it.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Use the supplied ritual role, ritual title, behavior, quality, and pawn status fields. Let quality shape confidence, aftermath, and emotional weight, but do not name or explain the quality label directly. Keep the entry grounded in what completion would feel like from that role; do not invent ritual effects beyond the supplied outcome.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_Ability</defName>
    <label>ability</label>
    <eventType>Ability</eventType>
    <prompt>Write a successful pawn ability use as a concrete moment of focus, risk, or exertion.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Use the supplied ability name, category, target, and cooldown facts. Treat short-cooldown abilities as quick minor moments and long-cooldown abilities as rarer, weightier choices; do not invent extra effects.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_DayReflection</defName>
    <label>day reflection</label>
    <eventType>DayReflection</eventType>
    <prompt>Write an end-of-day reflection that weighs the day as a whole.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Choose the supplied moments that still sting, glow, or weigh on the pawn tonight instead of listing every event.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_QuadrumReflection</defName>
    <label>quadrum reflection</label>
    <eventType>QuadrumReflection</eventType>
    <prompt>Write a rare long reflection over a whole quadrum of the pawn's life.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Use the dated highlights as anchors across time. Mention dates naturally, connect several events into a broader life reflection, and do not list every highlight mechanically.</enhancement>
    <!-- Optional: set this to the model id of one configured API endpoint to force these longer entries there. -->
    <forcedModel></forcedModel>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_Progression</defName>
    <label>progression</label>
    <eventType>Progression</eventType>
    <prompt>Write a pawn progression moment as a concrete private diary entry about change, effort, status, or identity.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Use the supplied before-and-after fields exactly. Do not explain game mechanics, invent training scenes, or add powers, titles, body changes, or achievements that were not supplied.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_ArcReflection</defName>
    <label>arc reflection</label>
    <eventType>ArcReflection</eventType>
    <prompt>Write a rare life-arc diary entry about who the pawn is becoming across the selected memories.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Use the selected memories as anchors, not as a checklist. Connect only a few memories into a private sense of change, regret, pride, fear, or resolve. Do not mention every memory.</enhancement>
    <!-- Optional: set this to the model id of one configured API endpoint to force these longer entries there. -->
    <forcedModel></forcedModel>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_Arrival</defName>
    <label>arrival</label>
    <eventType>Arrival</eventType>
    <prompt>Write a factual colony-arrival note about how this pawn joined or began here.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Make the arrival feel like a threshold: dust, shock, silence, relief, suspicion, or first sight of shelter. Use only scenario and arrival facts.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_Death</defName>
    <label>death</label>
    <eventType>Death</eventType>
    <prompt>Write a factual death note about how the colonist died.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Make the death note stark and specific, with one concrete cause or setting detail. Use only supplied cause, body-part, weapon, condition, and setting facts; keep it brief.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <!-- Royalty R2 persona lifecycle. Exact rows provide edge-specific guidance; the broad row is
       the safe fallback for compatibility events that retain the PersonaWeapon domain. -->
  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_PersonaWeapon</defName>
    <label>persona weapon bond</label>
    <eventType>PersonaWeapon</eventType>
    <prompt>Write an exact persona-weapon bond lifecycle change from the bonded pawn&apos;s point of view.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Use only the supplied weapon, lifecycle states, duration, prior bond, ending cause, and selected trait facts. Treat the weapon as present and uncanny without inventing dialogue, conscious motives, combat, or a death.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_PersonaWeaponBondFormed</defName>
    <label>persona weapon bond formed</label>
    <eventType>PersonaWeaponBondFormed</eventType>
    <prompt>Write the moment an exact persona-weapon bond formed.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Center first contact, recognition, obligation, or unease grounded in the supplied weapon and traits. If an exact previous bonded pawn is supplied, acknowledge the transfer without inventing how it happened or what the weapon said.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_PersonaWeaponBondSeparated</defName>
    <label>persona weapon bond separated</label>
    <eventType>PersonaWeaponBondSeparated</eventType>
    <prompt>Write a persona-weapon bond&apos;s first meaningful period of separation.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Use the supplied separation duration and state change as absence, friction, jealousy, relief, or unease. This is not proof of destruction, abandonment, transfer, combat, or death.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_PersonaWeaponBondRecovered</defName>
    <label>persona weapon bond recovered</label>
    <eventType>PersonaWeaponBondRecovered</eventType>
    <prompt>Write the exact bonded pawn wielding a persona weapon again after a recorded separation.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Make return and recognition concrete through the supplied duration, weapon, and trait facts. Do not invent apology, dialogue, a fight, or what happened while they were apart.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_PersonaWeaponBondEnded</defName>
    <label>persona weapon bond ended</label>
    <eventType>PersonaWeaponBondEnded</eventType>
    <prompt>Write the standalone ending of an exact persona-weapon bond.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Use the supplied ending cause and bond duration to make finality specific. Do not invent a death, attacker, battle, transfer, or last words beyond the exact facts.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <!-- Royalty R3 reuses the Tale owner but needs exact first-kill guidance. -->
  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_PersonaWeaponFirstConsequentialKill</defName>
    <label>first consequential persona-weapon kill</label>
    <eventType>PersonaWeaponFirstConsequentialKill</eventType>
    <prompt>Write the exact bonded wielder&apos;s first consequential kill with this persona weapon.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Use only the supplied victim, source Tale, weapon, bond state, and selected trait facts. Keep the killer as the sole point of view; do not invent dialogue, motives for the weapon, another attack, or the victim&apos;s inner experience.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <!-- Royalty R4 exact title/psylink mutation owners. These keys are plain source defName strings;
       they are not cross-references to paid-DLC Defs and remain inert when Royalty is absent. -->
  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_RoyalTitleGained</defName>
    <label>first royal title</label>
    <eventType>RoyalTitleGained</eventType>
    <prompt>Write the pawn receiving their first exact title in the supplied royal faction.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Preserve the faction, new title, and cause exactly. Show first rank as recognition, obligation, pride, or unease; do not invent a ceremony, duties, or faction mechanics.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_RoyalTitlePromoted</defName>
    <label>royal promotion</label>
    <eventType>RoyalTitlePromoted</eventType>
    <prompt>Write an exact promotion from the supplied previous title to the new title in one faction.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Keep both titles and the faction correct. Optional supplied duty changes may color the reaction, but do not list mechanics or invent a bestowing ceremony.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_RoyalTitleDemoted</defName>
    <label>royal demotion</label>
    <eventType>RoyalTitleDemoted</eventType>
    <prompt>Write an exact demotion from the supplied previous title to the lower title in one faction.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Keep both titles and the faction correct. Center loss of standing, relief, shame, anger, or changed responsibility without inventing blame or political events.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_RoyalTitleLost</defName>
    <label>royal title lost</label>
    <eventType>RoyalTitleLost</eventType>
    <prompt>Write the complete loss of the supplied previous royal title in its exact faction.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Treat the new title value none as complete loss, not promotion or transfer. Use only the supplied cause; do not invent death, succession, punishment, or a replacement title.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_PsylinkLevel</defName>
    <label>psylink gain</label>
    <eventType>PsylinkLevel</eventType>
    <prompt>Write the exact supplied psylink level increase and its known or unknown cause.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Preserve the before/after levels and cause. Write lived psychic sensation, responsibility, or unease without naming unprovided powers or explaining implant and ritual mechanics.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_BestowingCeremony</defName>
    <label>royal bestowing ceremony</label>
    <eventType>BestowingCeremony</eventType>
    <prompt>Write the completed imperial bestowing ceremony from the supplied ritual role.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Use the exact mutation pawn, faction, title before/after, psylink before/after, and imperial_bestowing cause when present. Keep all changes in this ritual page; do not invent honors, speeches, powers, or another progression scene.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_AnimaTreeLinking</defName>
    <label>anima linking ceremony</label>
    <eventType>AnimaTreeLinking</eventType>
    <prompt>Write the completed anima linking ceremony from the supplied ritual role.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Use the exact psylink before/after and anima_linking cause when present. Keep the psychic change in this ritual page and do not invent powers, imperial rank, or extra ritual effects.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

  <!-- Broad-domain fallback for integration-API events (see INTEGRATIONS.md). Adapter mods can
       ship a narrower DiaryEventPromptDef keyed by their eventKey or group defName; this row only
       catches External events with no more specific policy loaded. -->
  <PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>
    <defName>DiaryEventPrompt_External</defName>
    <label>external mod event</label>
    <eventType>External</eventType>
    <prompt>Write a moment reported by another mod as something the pawn just lived through.</prompt>
    <enhancement>Stay strictly inside the supplied event line and context facts; do not invent mechanics, systems, or unstated participants.</enhancement>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryEventPromptDef>

</Defs>
