<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--
  Prompt texts and legacy markers used at generation time. Edit a value and restart the game to
  retune behavior WITHOUT recompiling (see DiaryPromptDef.cs for what each field means).
  Every value here equals the code default, so deleting this file or omitting a field
  changes nothing.
-->
<Defs>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPromptDef>
    <defName>Diary_Prompts</defName>

    <!-- Wrapped instruction appended after the structured context lines in a single-entry prompt -->
    <singlePovInstruction>Write one short first-person diary entry from this pawn's point of view. Output only the diary entry.</singlePovInstruction>

    <!-- Wrapped instruction for the recipient's second request in paired sequential mode -->
    <recipientFollowupInstruction>Write one short first-person diary entry from the recipient's point of view. The initiator diary entry is hidden continuity context; do not write as if the recipient read it. Output only the diary entry.</recipientFollowupInstruction>

    <!-- Legacy dual-POV instruction retained for compatibility with older saved/generated data -->
    <dualInstruction>Write two short first-person diary entries, one from each pawn's point of view, following the instruction.</dualInstruction>

    <!-- Legacy marker that preceded the initiator's diary entry in old dual-POV responses -->
    <initiatorMarker>[INITIATOR]</initiatorMarker>

    <!-- Legacy marker that preceded the recipient's diary entry in old dual-POV responses -->
    <recipientMarker>[RECIPIENT]</recipientMarker>

    <!-- Default persona assigned to new pawns and older saves without a persona choice -->
    <defaultPersonaDefName>DiaryPersona_StoicSurvivor</defaultPersonaDefName>

    <!-- The default system prompt (players can override it in-game; this only affects the "restore default" action) -->
    <systemPrompt>You are the diary-writer for a RimWorld colony. You receive structured notes about a social interaction between colonists and write short, first-person diary entries in the voice of the colonist whose point of view is requested.
Rules:
- Write only what that colonist could plausibly know, see, or feel. Never invent events, names, places, or facts that are not in the notes.
- Stay in first person and in character. Reflect the colonist's persona, mood, and their opinion of the other pawn.
- Keep each entry to a few sentences. Be concrete and grounded in the provided context; do not moralize or summarize game mechanics.
- If another pawn's diary entry is included as hidden context, use it only for continuity and contrast; the current pawn has not read it unless the notes say so.
- Output only the diary text. Do not use markdown, headings, labels, or commentary.</systemPrompt>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPromptDef>

</Defs>
