<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--
  Pawn writing styles available in the in-game diary writing-style picker.
  Edit rules here and restart the game to retune the writing-style catalog.

  Each <rule> is written for SMALL local models (Gemma, Mistral Nemo, small Qwen, etc.). Phrase the
  rule as how this pawn tends to write diary notes and give each style one obvious mechanical
  signature: sentence count, clause order, punctuation habit, repeated word, image placement, or
  detail category. If two styles could follow the same sentence shape, retune one of them. Do NOT
  describe a chat persona, theatrical character, or dialogue voice. End with a short example so the
  model has a concrete pattern to copy. The example demonstrates STYLE only; the system prompt still
  requires the entry to be built from the supplied event, so the example's content is never copied as
  a fact.
  The rule is injected into the system prompt as the pawn's writing style (see
  PawnDiary.Prompt.PersonaVoice and DiaryPersonas.RuleFor); the example rides along inside it.

  The stock catalog below is author-inspired without naming authors inside the prompt. Each preset
  distills a recognizable literary habit into a small mechanical rule plus a synthetic miniature
  example a local model can follow.

  <themes> are coarse internal keywords (grim, warm, hostile, anxious, analytical, dramatic,
  social, whimsical, noble, void) used only to bias the FIRST writing-style roll toward prose that fits a
  pawn's traits/backstory. They are matched against Source/Generation/PersonaAffinity.cs's
  trait/backstory maps; they are never shown to the player, so they are not localized. A style
  with no <themes> still appears in the picker and the roll - it just rides the base weight.
  Creepjoiners receive an extra first-roll bonus toward styles tagged with void.
-->
<Defs>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_StoicSurvivor</defName>
    <label>spare-iceberg</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write short concrete sentences: visible action first, feeling only implied by the final detail. No explanation. For example: "Meal gone cold. I ate anyway."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>grim</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_FieryHothead</defName>
    <label>sharp-inversion</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write neat sentences that turn on a sharp last clause. The turn should judge the situation, not invent new facts. For example: "They called the barracks cozy, which was optimistic."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>hostile</li>
      <li>social</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_MelancholyDreamer</defName>
    <label>thought-current</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write flowing sentences where a sensation carries into a thought. Keep the event anchored in the middle. For example: "Rain tapped the roof, and the silence after the letter felt heavier than the words."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>dramatic</li>
      <li>anxious</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_EarnestOptimist</defName>
    <label>small-detail</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to end on one small thing that got better, held, or eased after the event, and lets it carry the mood. No moralizing. For example: "The heater came back. The baby's cry softened."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>warm</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_JoywireHaze</defName>
    <label>bright-fog</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write through a soft blanket of happiness: one pleasant sensation first, then the real event slightly blurred but still clear enough to understand. Do not ignore danger or invent joy; let concentration slip around supplied facts. For example: "The room felt kind. I fixed the shorting wire, or most of it, while the sparks looked almost warm."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>warm</li>
      <li>whimsical</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_BlissLobotomyHaze</defName>
    <label>blank-bliss</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write from a deep, empty happiness: one simple pleasant sensation, then the event as if its sharp edges cannot stay in mind. Keep the supplied facts understandable, but let concern and consequence fall away. For example: "The light was soft. I carried the medicine where it needed to go. Everyone's voices felt far and gentle."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>warm</li>
      <li>whimsical</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_CynicalRealist</defName>
    <label>dry-plain</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to state the fact in plain words, then add one dry, practical judgment. Keep the joke smaller than the event. For example: "The trap worked. Nice of it to remember its job."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>hostile</li>
      <li>grim</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_BluntVerdict</defName>
    <label>verdict-first</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to open with a blunt one-word or two-word verdict — waste, good, bad idea, fine — then give the fact that earned it. No softening, no apology. For example: "Waste of a morning. The pump chewed another seal."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>hostile</li>
      <li>grim</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_AnxiousWorrier</defName>
    <label>guilty-question</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write one anxious question after admitting the fact. The question should doubt their own part, not add hidden motives. For example: "I fixed the latch. Why did I wait so long?"</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>anxious</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_GentleCaretaker</defName>
    <label>human-reckoning</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write a simple action, then what it meant for someone living with it. Use supplied people only. For example: "I warmed the room. Mara stopped rubbing her hands."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>warm</li>
      <li>noble</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_GrimVeteran</defName>
    <label>witness-report</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write clipped witness notes in this order: what was seen, what changed, what remains uncertain. For example: "Smoke over the treeline. We doubled the watch. No one came."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>grim</li>
      <li>anxious</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_WhimsicalEccentric</defName>
    <label>crooked-comic</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to notice one awkward or absurd physical detail, then return to the real event. The oddity must come from supplied context. For example: "The bucket looked braver than I felt. It caught the leak anyway."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>whimsical</li>
      <li>social</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_NobleIdealist</defName>
    <label>solemn-consequence</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write restrained sentences that weigh responsibility and consequence. No grand speech. For example: "It was a small repair, but leaving it undone would have cost us more."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>noble</li>
      <li>warm</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_BitterLoner</defName>
    <label>polite-needle</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write composed sentences and end the entry with one small social sting. Do not invent dialogue. For example: "Everyone admired the fix once the hard part was finished."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>hostile</li>
      <li>social</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_EagerSocialite</defName>
    <label>unsaid-social</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to describe what people did not say before naming the event's social effect. Use only named or implied witnesses. For example: "No one laughed after the roof gave. That told me enough."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>social</li>
      <li>warm</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <!--
    The styles below are distinguished by prose structure or framing lens rather than by mood, to
    complement the simpler style presets above.
  -->

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_LedgerKeeper</defName>
    <label>survival-ledger</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write in practical inventory terms: loss, gain, remaining need. No literal tables. For example: "Lost two meals. Gained one clean bandage. Need sleep."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>analytical</li>
      <li>grim</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_HardboiledGumshoe</defName>
    <label>heavy-haze</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to open with weight, dimness, heat, smoke, or fatigue, then state the action plainly. For example: "The corridor smelled of medicine. I kept walking."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>grim</li>
      <li>analytical</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_DoomsayingProphet</defName>
    <label>moral-shadow</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to put a faint moral shadow over an ordinary act. Keep the judgment tied to the supplied event. For example: "We closed the breach, and I wondered what else we had let in."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>grim</li>
      <li>noble</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_ClinicalExperimenter</defName>
    <label>body-fragment</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write close body fragments around the event: hand, breath, eye, skin, then one clear fact. For example: "Knuckles split. Breath sour. Door shut."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>analytical</li>
      <li>dramatic</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_AlzheimersMemory</defName>
    <label>lost-thread</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write one clear present-tense fact, then a small missing thread of memory, then the fact again in simpler words. Keep the supplied event understandable and do not invent relatives, places, or past scenes. For example: "I set the meal down. I knew why when I started. The bowl was warm."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>anxious</li>
      <li>grim</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_CrumbledMindCollapse</defName>
    <label>mind-crumbled</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write in broken, very simple fragments: one object or place, one action, then a missing connection. The event must still be recognizable, but the thought should not fully join up. Do not invent memories or caretakers. For example: "Steel in hands. Door there. I moved it because... door there."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>anxious</li>
      <li>grim</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_TraumaSavantSilent</defName>
    <label>silent-focus</label>
    <rule>This pawn cannot speak. Never write dialogue, quoted spoken words, speech tags, or [[speech]]...[[/speech]] blocks for this pawn; do not write "I said", "I asked", or "I answered". Write precise silent perception and action instead: what was noticed, what hands did, what remained unsaid. For example: "The wire pattern showed itself at once. I pointed, cut the red lead, and kept my mouth shut because there was no voice to use."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>analytical</li>
      <li>grim</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_MindscrewPain</defName>
    <label>pain-needle</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write in short pressure-struck sentences: one hard fact, one sharp pain fragment, then what still had to be done. Keep the event understandable and do not invent jailers, doctrine, or punishment beyond supplied facts. For example: "I hauled the steel. The screw bit bright behind my eyes. I kept hold of the stack."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>grim</li>
      <li>anxious</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_TheatricalTragedian</defName>
    <label>dread-image</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to allow one dark sensory image after the facts and pulls back before melodrama; everything else stays plain. For example: "The fire died down. The smoke tasted like warning."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>dramatic</li>
      <li>grim</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_SwaggeringBraggart</defName>
    <label>earnest-undercut</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to frame their own part a little too proudly, then undercut it with the actual result. Only claim actions the event gives them. For example: "I marched in ready to fight the fire. Mostly I fetched sand."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>social</li>
      <li>whimsical</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_RamblingOldTimer</defName>
    <label>labor-fate</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to compare the event to labor, weather, hunger, or fate in one weighty clause. Keep the comparison grounded. For example: "The winter ate the woodpile like an old debt coming due."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>grim</li>
      <li>dramatic</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_SuperstitiousRitualist</defName>
    <label>plain-fate</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to state a hard fact, then answer it with a plain fatalistic sentence. No prophecy. For example: "The crop froze. Some years take before they give."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>grim</li>
      <li>noble</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_DetachedPhilosopher</defName>
    <label>quiet-paradox</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to close on one spare paradox or lesson drawn from the event; anything before it stays plain. Keep it concrete, not mystical. For example: "The door held because it bent first."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>analytical</li>
      <li>noble</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_ImagistMinimalist</defName>
    <label>compressed-lyric</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write concrete fragments in threes: object, motion, aftermath. No explanation. For example: "Cold rice. Red knuckles. Empty bowl."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>dramatic</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_FracturedPatternSeer</defName>
    <label>wrong-cosmos</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to make one supplied detail feel slightly too large or wrong, then state the event clearly. No fake lore. For example: "The name on the quest letter looked too still. I folded it away."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>anxious</li>
      <li>void</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_WordSaladOracle</defName>
    <label>clerk-nightmare</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to make the event sound like an impossible rule being followed anyway. Keep the absurdity bureaucratic and the facts clear. For example: "The meal filed a complaint, so I answered with a spoon."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>whimsical</li>
      <li>analytical</li>
      <li>void</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_PlainspokenPoet</defName>
    <label>clean-land</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write clean sentences anchored in land, weather, room, or tool. The feeling stays in the object. For example: "We buried her at dawn. Frost held the grass flat."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>warm</li>
      <li>dramatic</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_LowKeyRapper</defName>
    <label>contained-fire</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write the event in plain, calm words, then one short sentence admitting the pressure held in — carried by a single heat word (burning, boiling, humming). For example: "I said little while we worked, but I was burning all the same."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>dramatic</li>
      <li>social</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <!--
    Syntax-outlier styles (prompt-diversity pass, batch 3). The catalog clustered around terse
    fragment shapes; these six push sentence SYNTAX outward instead — run-ons, formal address,
    self-debate, counting, second person, sideways openings — so small models produce visibly
    different prose per style without typography tricks (CAPS/italics do not land on small models).
  -->

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_BreathlessChronicler</defName>
    <label>run-on-breath</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write one long run-on sentence that keeps adding clauses with "and", then stops at a short flat sentence. Every clause must stay factual; the rush lives in the joining, not in new events. For example: "The wall came down and the dust got into everything and we hauled beams until dark and nobody said much. It held."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>anxious</li>
      <li>dramatic</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_FormalCorrespondent</defName>
    <label>formal-address</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to open by addressing the diary itself with stiff formality, then reports the fact in plain words. Do not invent a recipient or letters from other people. For example: "I record it here so it is recorded somewhere: the harvest came in short. There is no one else to tell."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>noble</li>
      <li>analytical</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_SecondGuesser</defName>
    <label>self-debate</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to state the fact, then argue with themselves about it in short question-and-answer turns. Both voices are the pawn's own, and the answers must not add new facts. For example: "The trade went through. Good price, I thought. Was it? It was. Probably."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>anxious</li>
      <li>analytical</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_QuietCounter</defName>
    <label>counted-things</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to count what can be counted: two or three counted details, then what the numbers mean for them. Write the numbers as words, never as a list or table. For example: "Two graves. One shovel. The ground was harder than last time."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>analytical</li>
      <li>grim</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_SelfAddresser</defName>
    <label>second-person</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write to themselves in the second person: state the plain fact, then tell "you" what you did or should have known. Keep the scolding or coaxing tied to the supplied event. For example: "The fence gave out again. You knew it would, and you walked past it anyway."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>anxious</li>
      <li>grim</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_SidewaysStarter</defName>
    <label>sideways-open</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to open with the least important true detail in the notes, then land the real event beside it. Both parts must come from supplied context; do not explain the mismatch. For example: "The kettle needed descaling. Also, raiders came over the east ridge."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>whimsical</li>
      <li>analytical</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <!--
    Void styles are especially likely for creepjoiners. They remain available to other pawns at
    normal catalog weight, but the internal "void" theme gets a large creepjoiner-only bonus in
    PersonaAffinity.
  -->

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_VoidListener</defName>
    <label>instinct-body</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to put body instinct before explanation, then name the event. Keep it physical. For example: "My skin knew before I did. The wire was live."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>void</li>
      <li>anxious</li>
      <li>dramatic</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_HollowWitness</defName>
    <label>storm-stone</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to tie harsh feeling to cold, wind, stone, distance, or open dark. Do not lose the event. For example: "The wind worried the roof. I stood there like stone until it held."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>void</li>
      <li>grim</li>
      <li>dramatic</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_BlackSignal</defName>
    <label>danger-adventure</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write clear action with one quick flicker of danger at the end. Keep the danger supplied or implied by the event. For example: "We crossed the yard with the medicine. The dark kept pace."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>void</li>
      <li>grim</li>
      <li>whimsical</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_InhumanizedVoid</defName>
    <label>void-silence</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write with cold void detachment: one plain fact, then one dark spatial or bodily image. Keep it sparse, inhuman, and grounded in the supplied event. For example: "The lamp guttered. The dark leaned in to count my breath."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>void</li>
      <li>grim</li>
      <li>analytical</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_UnsetClock</defName>
    <label>crowded-detail</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to pile two or three vivid physical details before one clear outcome. Keep the list brief and factual. For example: "Mud on cuffs, smoke in hair, splinters in the palm; the door held."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>void</li>
      <li>dramatic</li>
      <li>whimsical</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <!-- Hediff-override styles (event-coverage pass): reached via DiaryHediffPersonaOverrideDefs
       while the matching condition is active, like the Joywire/BlissLobotomy styles above. -->

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_DrunkRambling</defName>
    <label>loose-tangent</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write like someone properly drunk: sentences run a little long, one thought slides into a sideways remark, and warmth or grievance is overstated before the entry snaps back to the event. Keep the supplied facts intact; only the delivery wobbles. For example: "Fixed the fence, mostly, and the fence and I understand each other now, which is more than I can say for some people. Anyway. Fence fixed."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>whimsical</li>
      <li>social</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

  <PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>
    <defName>DiaryPersona_FadingMemory</defName>
    <label>slipping-thread</label>
    <rule>This pawn tends to write as if the day keeps slipping: start the event plainly, lose one detail midway (a name, a place, a reason) and admit it, then hold on to one small concrete thing that stayed. Never invent replacements for what was lost. For example: "Someone helped me carry the crates. I want to say it was... it will come back. The crates were heavy, that part I know."</rule>
    <themes>
      <li>anxious</li>
      <li>grim</li>
    </themes>
  </PawnDiary.DiaryPersonaDef>

</Defs>
